Krish NAik: Yeah, hello everyone, good morning.
Krish NAik: Please check which houses are opened or not.
Krish NAik: Everyone, please just try to type in the charts, and I will get a confirmation.
Krish NAik: Perfect, thanks.
Krish NAik: Fine, so, today…
Krish NAik: I think yesterday I've already shared the repo and all the links that I have shared, okay? So, it is available, you guys can have a look into that.
Krish NAik: So, let me just trade… we'll just close…
Krish NAik: Ruth is asking, good morning, Saurangshu, the NL SQL query table, I believe, can be better and easily realized,
Krish NAik: Using MCP along with SQL model. Yes, you can do that, but I feel that SQL table retriever is better, because there…
Krish NAik: For every table, you don't need to pass the context, so we need to fetch only the tables based on the query, so I feel that is better.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me start,
Krish NAik: the official one. Today, a little bit about,
Krish NAik: one or that I'll be talking, and then we guys can actually take the clone.
Krish NAik: So, just wait, this is desktop 3, I think, okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, so yesterday, the things that I have told, how many of you have done? Setting up your, Superbase.
Krish NAik: That was one requirement, based on the current data that we have.
Krish NAik: Please share the repo, I was having office. I'll write the repo is there in Notion, please have it checked. In Notion, it's there.
Krish NAik: Okay, whoever is asking, please check the notion.
Krish NAik: Oh, like… So, I think, whereas in my report, there are a lot of things.
Krish NAik: Let me just open…
Krish NAik: Alright, so, first of all, everyone take a clone of the latest one, okay, the report that I have, pushed. Okay, everybody, like, please take the clone of this one. A lot of things that, might have changed.
Krish NAik: So, that part… so just be sure you are updated with me. You can do a simple git pull, and just be sure the exact… So, take a clone, and then create a virtual environment. I think already I've shared the requirement.txt, so majorly, I think all the necessary requirements we do have.
Krish NAik: there.
Krish NAik: Okay, everybody, please set up your environments.
Krish NAik: Always, whenever we are starting a project, create a new virtual environment, do the installation of the packages.
Krish NAik: And then finally, configure your… Environment variable.
Krish NAik: Because I think with respect to your environment variables.
Krish NAik: Okay, immediately I'm working with OpenAI. So, OpenAI is there, Pinebone API key that needs to be passed. Then comes your database URL. Okay, so here, in multiple ways, you don't need to pass it.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so just get the main string. That is fine.
Krish NAik: Then comes OPEC API key, this you can configure later on. Right now, not necessary. For VANA configuration, again, keep this thing same exactly.
Krish NAik: I think application settings, and the rest of everything, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… everybody please take the clone.
Krish NAik: It is available in Notion, please check your Notions.
Krish NAik: Today, little bit, with respect to text-to-SQL extension that we'll be talking about, okay? And then, finally, we will jump. So, I think this is your project too, you can have a check. The report is there.
Krish NAik: Yes, VANA supports everything, okay? So, if I go to the docs, quickly, I'll be showing you, because the notebook is already ready for me. Okay, so connect to your own database, I'm just showing you, like, configure your LLM, you can simply do, like, Anthropic, Azure, OpenAI, Gemini, Ulama, okay? So, pretty much everything is there.
Krish NAik: Then comes, your databases, Postgres, MySQL, MSQL, Snowflake, BigQuery, ClickHouse, Oracle, Presto, Hive, okay, even custom, things that can also be added. Okay, so this is pretty much…
Krish NAik: A lot of functionalities are there, so…
Krish NAik: Little bit today, based on Superface, I will be making the connection. I think my supervis…
Krish NAik: Well, even I forgot, okay, this is not my main account, it looks like, yes.
Krish NAik: Yes, we are doing the second project.
Krish NAik: So, my supervisor is already configured the same thing that I have asked you guys. So, in your case, you will see, like, 3 tables are there. The schema was already provided. So, I hope everybody has done that part yesterday that we have discussed.
Krish NAik: Right now, based on your connection string,
Krish NAik: you can have a test. Okay, so before doing the testing, first of all, just be sure everything is configured in your .env file, so whatever the things that are there. At least keep your OpenAI API key and,
Krish NAik: I think that is the major requirement right now.
Krish NAik: Because for Vana, so this is the notebook that I will be using.
Krish NAik: So, docs… I think docs here…
Krish NAik: No, not this talks notebook. Yes, I think this is a notebook.
Krish NAik: So just be sure, inside the notebook, you have the .env file.
Krish NAik: Okay, and just do the installation of the packages within your virtual environment. Everybody, please do that.
Krish NAik: And then, check the import section is working fine or not.
Krish NAik: The database error column segment, does not exist.
Krish NAik: Alright, oops, we are telling something like that…
Krish NAik: Okay, we'll just share that, where is superbase? Superbase…
Krish NAik: I think in your SQL editor… okay.
Krish NAik: Just have a check, this part, I will be adding it in motion. Okay, sure.
Krish NAik: It won't.
Krish NAik: Okay? Showam, check this part.
Krish NAik: Check this, SQL schema.
Krish NAik: Alright, so once you guys have done the configuration, please let me know that, yes, we are ready.
Krish NAik: Because once you have done the installation of the packages, the next step that comes is configuring your OpenAI key.
Krish NAik: Yes, for now, just keep the, OpenAIT only, so if I show you my notebooks…
Krish NAik: Majorly, you need the database URL also for the Subabase project. Okay, so keep that also in your mind.
Krish NAik: the database URL and the OpenAI API key, these two are required. Everybody, please do configure for the existing notebook to be checked.
Krish NAik: Yesterday's schema was different. The one that I told yesterday only, I told… you have a separate schema for this particular project. Very similar only, but a little bit different as it can be.
Krish NAik: In the last class, I have repeated so many times, do the setup, do the setup.
Krish NAik: What will be the database URL? The connection string, yes, it is connection string that you have, that will be the…
Krish NAik: You want it.
Krish NAik: So, for example, here, the superbase part, where is the superbase?
Krish NAik: No, this is one, yes. From here, when you go to connect, this becomes your entire connection string.
Krish NAik: I'm using Direct Connection, it works for me. Okay, in your case, I would check on that.
Krish NAik: I took from the projects repo, yes. If the project repo you are using, then no issues.
Krish NAik: Natcheme is asking, without using, Vana, do we have to write an MCP server to understand SQL? Do we have to write an MCP server? Why an MCP server unique?
Krish NAik: There is no requirement of an MCP server.
Krish NAik: It got created, thank you, alright. So, just check this schema, I've shared it in the Notion also. If somebody, require it, copy-paste it from there, and please do the setup.
Krish NAik: It's a notion, naga, check Notion. Everybody please have a check on the nation as well as the GitHub, always.
Krish NAik: This is the same directly as the DB string that I have passed it, guys, as simple as that. This entire thing is inside my DB URL. Okay, so, as you will see. Separately, I have not mentioned everything.
Krish NAik: The rest of the configuration doesn't matter. At least keep the database URL and the OpenAI API key. I think these two are the major requirements for now, for the notebook execution of this text-to-SQL complete.
Krish NAik: And keep the ENV file within the notebook folder.
Krish NAik: And it should be recognized.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think this is the one, yes.
Krish NAik: Once you have done the installation, please have it checked. Okay, so according to your service that you are using, okay, a quick, thing that I'm going to let you know. For example, if you want to use a different LLM service.
Krish NAik: Okay, this LLM only needs to be changed. Okay, so for example, you can directly go to the documentation.
Krish NAik: And then, for example, if you want to work with Gemini. Okay, so here you have that Gemini. You have to just…
Krish NAik: Update this input based on your requirement.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always look into this, configure your LLM, because the database will be fixed, you don't need to do, but if you want to use your custom LLMs with VANAI, just be sure you are installing that package. It means that if I am using OpenAI, you will see that pip installed VANA fast API with Open…
Krish NAik: AI.coms. If I change it to Gemini, then this package gets changed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so according to your LLM, please install the… Package?
Krish NAik: Okay, and just be sure the imports are correct.
Krish NAik: Sample dataset already shared, naga.
Krish NAik: You have the create sample file within your data. Yesterday, I already told about that.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, see, the schema, already it's there in… from Notion, you can pick it up. Already, I've shared it in the GitHub repo. Yesterday, I've shown you that part. Again, I'm repeating myself.
Krish NAik: Where is this one? Yes. So…
Krish NAik: inside your data, you have this creative generate a sampledata.py, as well as within the SQL folder, you have the schema.sql also. Okay? So, just like in the last class I have shown you, you need to do the same thing, and you need to do the setup.
Krish NAik: No, this is not yesterday's data. Yesterday's data was different.
Krish NAik: So once you guys are ready with the setup, please let me know in the chat that, yes, I am ready, then we won.
Krish NAik: Rakshmi's asking if I don't want to use VANA AI agent. Okay, if you don't want to use VANA, it's not necessary.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: then you have to, create your own custom, like, driver through that particular, like, SQL alchemy, through that particular mechanism. You have to connect it through your SQL Server. That will be a manual connection.
Krish NAik: Okay, just take your time fine, I know. The first time you're doing it, so the setup will take time, but do it step by step. Just be sure your supervisor is ready. Okay, then, Pinecone. Okay, in Pinecone, you have to create, two indexes.
Krish NAik: So, the first part, complete the super waste part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I will just go here.
Krish NAik: Let me just, switch on my one, okay? And then you respond at the interview.
Krish NAik: Because, first of all, I want that, things…
Krish NAik: To be done in the first step.
Krish NAik: Let me pick out it…
Krish NAik: Let me just reload the service, because even I have to check few APIs, whether it's working or not.
Krish NAik: I will do the testing in front of India.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once you have configured the SuperBase, okay, so I'm just… because I have already told the prerequisite yesterday, okay, and you can mention it in Notion.
Krish NAik: at least OpenAI API key for my requirement. You can work with Gemini also, you can use your Pinecone account. In there, I'll be using TextEmbitting 3 small from OpenAI, and for Postgres Connection, I'll be using Superbase.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, first of all, configure your Superbase. I think OpenAI API key, you guys will be having, most of you. If you want to use Gemini, then do the configuration for that.
Krish NAik: And then finally comes your Pinecone account.
Krish NAik: Can you show how to create an index?
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: How to create an index, I can show you.
Krish NAik: Before we land.
Krish NAik: Well, this is pretty much easy when I get confused. Where is my Pinebone is? So, here, one, you will be having the Spinebone account.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you have the option of creating text. You will go here, you have to select what type of embedding configuration that you want to do. So, for example, I'll be working with text embedding 3 small.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this particular is the large one, don't select the large one, just be sure you are working with the small. Now, small has two different variants, so just be sure the dimensions are 1536, because we'll be working with the 1536 dimension.
Krish NAik: I don't have the option of creating, indexes.
Krish NAik: Because I think this is free, so we can create limited one. Probably I will delete them.
Krish NAik: I'm mine.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me just stop this one.
Krish NAik: Let me just delete my index. So, I will go here…
Krish NAik: Index is 3 index, let me just dealt everything.
Krish NAik: I'm just cleaning out everything from my mind.
Krish NAik: Now, Naga is asking, confused. We are creating table in Pinecone? Who creates table in Pinecone? Nobody creates tables and vector databases.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, first of all, guys, everybody please look. Okay, just log in to your Pinecone account, okay? So, first of all, you need the first index I am creating from scratch, and I think this is pretty much easy, anybody can do it. I'm using text embedding 3 small.
Krish NAik: From here, I'll be changing the dimension. That is the only requirement, okay? And then, you can directly pass. So here, for example, rag-documents is one that I'll be passing. Now, this configuration is available in my code, okay? So if you want to check the configuration.
Krish NAik: So, for example, here, inside your app, inside your config, somewhere that configuration will be there. Can you see here, rack documents?
Krish NAik: And what is the, Pinecone? So, I will be using US East 1AWS, okay? So, from here, this particular option of RAG, AWS, Serverless is fine, I will just create the index.
Krish NAik: Now, Ravi is asking, what is the purpose of index in Pinecone? What is the purpose of index? It's a vector database. I'm using Pinecone first time in this course, I think. Previously, I've discussed other vector databases. There is no purpose, it is a vector DB.
Krish NAik: There is no specific requirement that I have to use. I can use any.
Krish NAik: Okay, so the first index is done, and right now you need this RAC documents only.
Krish NAik: the other index… I will be using it at, which is the VANA SQL training one, but, your major index will be this rack document.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody, just be sure you are creating this and have a check that the dimension is 1536. If you select a different dimension, simply will get an error.
Krish NAik: Is there an index per document? No, no, no, no. Why per document, you will be creating an index? Inside an index, you will be creating multiple documents.
Krish NAik: Yes, I'm on the free plan.
Krish NAik: I am on the free plan, this is not my production account.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: This is a free account, I'm not using anything paid, so for you guys also, I know it should be up and working.
Krish NAik: Check.
Krish NAik: So our object.
Krish NAik: Before asking, check, what is the dimension directly?
Krish NAik: Okay, I think everybody has created the index. Please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I will be creating another index, okay, but I won't be using it, okay? So you guys want to create it or not, totally up to you.
Krish NAik: This one also, I'll be keeping it for now.
Krish NAik: One SQL training, I think, okay? Let me just check my configuration, a lot of things are there.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is a VANA SQL training, okay?
Krish NAik: Because right now, I won't be doing any SQL training, but later on, I plan to add that feature also.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I think two indexes are ready.
Krish NAik: In my case, put it back to intensity.
Krish NAik: Fine. So, just be sure you have created the RAC document index.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think everybody has created, and please let me know in the chat. The Pinecone index is done, and the superbase part is done.
Krish NAik: Yes or no? Please let me know in the chat, everyone. Superbase yesterday, I've already shown.
Krish NAik: While creating a pinecone index, it takes less than 1 minute. Just click, click, click, done.
Krish NAik: Where do you mention the index in .env? It's not in .env, it will be in your config file.
Krish NAik: config.py, this file. Okay, sorry, please check that.
Krish NAik: Yes, I have kept it as well as in the ENV also, but, really, like, it's not necessary.
Krish NAik: Because from the ENV, it will be picked up.
Krish NAik: Because this will be overwritten. You can pass the same thing here also. That's why, if you use the same naming convention like I have, no issues. But if you give a custom naming convention, just be sure you are up to date in your config file, and in your .env file.
Krish NAik: Just keep one copy of .env inside that notebook, because for that, I need the OpenAI access.
Krish NAik: That's the only requirement.
Krish NAik: Okay, so even I have two envies, one I have kept it in the root folder, and the other one only for the notebook execution.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can give anything, but change in the quota.
Krish NAik: You can give any name, just be sure in the code also you are updating the same thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so step by step, all the requirements, let me just list it down.
Krish NAik: And everyone should be ready. So, first of all, okay, coming to set up virtual ANV.
Krish NAik: This is the first step. I hope everybody has done it.
Krish NAik: Then comes… Install packages.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your, I'm going…
Krish NAik: Index creation, okay? And even with the fine hooks, index creation, get the API key. Okay, so for example, if you go to your… somewhere around your API key, this section, you have to create an API key.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please get your API key, and keep it in your .env file. Everybody.
Krish NAik: Okay, this part I have not shown, so you guys can create API keys simply.
Krish NAik: Alright, so Pinecore index creation plus the API key.
Krish NAik: Once this part is done.
Krish NAik: Then, okay, so the Superbase setup yesterday that we talked about, already I've shared the schema in Notion, you can use that one, okay, or the other one that I have shared it, in the report. Okay, the superbase…
Krish NAik: TV creation.
Krish NAik: And, bonfigure.
Krish NAik: your.env.
Krish NAik: These are the simple steps. So, how many of you are done with these steps? Please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: All these steps are done. Okay, so for a verification, quickly you can open the notebook, and you can have it checked that at least… I think, this is the notebook that I have. Okay, just check that the first part is working, and just be sure you have this .env here.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, just check the import section is working fine or not in the notebook. If you are getting any error, really, you need to resolve that.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can use any GPT 4.0, 4.0 Mini.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody please check the import libraries of the notebook that I have shared. Is it working or not? Yes, 4O is expensive, but better for textured to SQL-based tasks.
Krish NAik: Issue with Azure OpenAI? What is the issue with Aish? There is no issue. If you want to use Azure OpenAI, use Azure OpenAI. I have no restriction in that.
Krish NAik: If it is not working, you have to figure it out.
Krish NAik: Because I know it will work.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please let me know the input library section is working or not in the notebook.
Krish NAik: Please let me know.
Krish NAik: you need to fix out… you need to find the issues with VANA. Generally, VANA doesn't create any issues in 2.0, it's pretty much stable as compared to the 1.2, the legacy version. So, okay, it's working.
Krish NAik: What about Oink?
Krish NAik: Oh, no, OPIC, leave it for now. OPIC in code, there is a condition, true or false. So, OPIC is not required.
Krish NAik: Okay, OPIC is not required, guys. OPIC later on next week, when we'll be talking with respect to that deployment, then I'll be showing you. Right now, observability is not. Right now, we have to look into the core functionality.
Krish NAik: Srini was Ravi is asking how to create the DB. Yesterday, I have already shown that, but…
Krish NAik: Okay, working even if the ENV is outside the notebook folder? Okay, fine. This is just a sanity check that I am doing, just keep it inside it. I felt I got an error there, so… Alright, so the first part,
Krish NAik: Okay, if the imports are working. Okay, so… now, let's get back to a little bit of VANA. Okay, you can test out the other things.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, based on your requirement, you can install the package, configure the LLM, configure your databases. So, really, the databases, people are using it in production. The VANA project is really a good one.
Krish NAik: So, generally, for text-to-SQL tasks, I always prefer Vana blindly, because really, I don't think a lot. So, this is the best one in the market as compared to, like, Lanshin and Llama Index. They are really not up to the mark.
Krish NAik: Then, comes, like, any type of VectorTV integrations that can also be done, Mailverse and others, through a custom, VectorTV class, you can do the implementation.
Krish NAik: Then comes user authentication here, so every time you have to perform a user authentication, even I will be doing it.
Krish NAik: Then, now, this is based on completing an agentic framework, like VANA 2.0 is pretty much, much more about the agents, the way they will be calling multiple tools.
Krish NAik: Now, in 1.0, it was separate, okay? So, here, we'll be creating a very similar type of agent, as written here. If you want server-based solutions, because right now, I'm not using it very specifically with FastAP or Flask, if you want to test this part, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this is your main solution, this is the main script that you can actually always use it.
Krish NAik: This is text-to-SQL. Whoever is asking what is Vanna AI, just look into this one. The page, what is 1AI? It's an user of our AI agent that connects LLM to your database. Any type of LLM that can be connected with your database.
Krish NAik: So, I've already shown you the list of databases, so connect to your own database. You can always check what are the databases which are available. Custom databases can also be, implemented through a custom class.
Krish NAik: For everybody, okay? It's just like the text-to-SQL task that I have done yesterday with Llama Index.
Krish NAik: Now, I've just switched the framework to VANA.
Krish NAik: One is much more powerful just to perform one task, text to SQL, or, like, natural language to SQL. That is the main purpose.
Krish NAik: Okay, I will be using Postgres, so this will be my configuration. Run a SQL tool and Postgres Runner. Can you see the connection string here? In your case, you'll be getting the connection string of Superbase.
Krish NAik: I hope you get it. Here, you have to pass your own connection string of supervis.
Krish NAik: Gaius, please let me know.
Krish NAik: this is the only configuration changes, then in the OpenAI part, again, you will be passing whichever model that you want to work with. GPT-5, GPT-5, 1, 5.2, okay? So, simple configurational changes.
Krish NAik: Now, I will come to the notebook. If the import section is working fine, then comes loading, because here I told two, two things that I need. The database URL, so… and my…
Krish NAik: Here, okay, so actually I need the database URL, which I already have, and then I need the OpenAI API page. The other things are not required from this notebook execution perspective.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a simple check, okay, alright. As you can see, my database and other connections are pretty much ready, so for you also.
Krish NAik: VANA not needed for notebook, VANA not needed for Notebook, Y won't be needed. You need to install VANA, otherwise your import section will only not work for anybody. If you don't install VANA, it will simply not work.
Krish NAik: Rajat is asking how to get the DB URL. Yesterday, I showed you that is… this is the DB URL.
Krish NAik: Guys, I told you, no, yesterday. Why, again, the same thing you guys are asking? This is the complete TV URL.
Krish NAik: I am not breaking it into host port, I have kept it in a single shot only.
Krish NAik: Okay. Now, you have a script also to check the connection is fine or not. Okay, so for example.
Krish NAik: You can use this particular script just for a confirmation of the superbaseContest.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want to do the verification, you can run this, so probably, like.
Krish NAik: If I see this one… just wait.
Krish NAik: Mmm, you read later on.
Krish NAik: contest, I think this is the file that I need.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can see your database will be shown that, whether it's connected or not, okay? So, now this test file is much easier, so here directly the database URL that you can pass. If you want to have a test, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Because I have kept the test here also.
Krish NAik: So, the first thing is getting the environment files and then loading it up into the memory.
Krish NAik: For our notebook execution, just be sure you are having that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now comes, the load environment variables.
Krish NAik: part is done. Okay, so I think for everybody, the starting two cells should be up and working. Please provide with a confirmation.
Krish NAik: Is it working or not?
Krish NAik: Okay? Up and working alright fine.
Krish NAik: Now, I will initialize the LLM service that I have, the OpenAI LLM service. Okay, now this import will be changed if you are working with Gemini or any other.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, in my import, so just be sure you change this one. Okay, so main two changes are required. One is this one, if your database changes, and based on the database changes, like, run SQL tool, this tool will also change.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so in my case, I'm working with OpenAI. If you have Gemini, please change the import and update it.
Krish NAik: Loading the environment variables, okay, now I have configured my LLM service. Now, I need to connect it to the superbase. Okay, so connection to the PostgreSQL using the connection string, or the DB URL in simple terms. The connection string is equal to the DB URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you will see… The initialization is done.
Krish NAik: Here, if there is some issue with respect to your connection, here you will simply get an error.
Krish NAik: there is no DB password, there is only one the database URL.
Krish NAik: Santosh.
Krish NAik: There is only one string. This is the string. The entire string has to be inside the DB URL. Just update your password, your password field. That only needs to be updated.
Krish NAik: Please let me know for how many of you the database initialization is done, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Working, the database, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Now, generally, like, tools to define what the agent can do, and we will register the runSQL tool. To run any type of, I can say, tools within Varma, first of all, you have to get the access to tools through an object. So right now, this is my tool registry. Under tool registry, you have all the tools.
Krish NAik: Right now, I'm taking an object of that, and through that, I am registering my local tool right now, which is the SQL runner, Postgres runner initialization that I have done. So you need to actually pass the database connection in the run SQL tool.
Krish NAik: And then you have to pass the access group. So, right now, I've kept it simple, the default one, user comma admin, so one level of authentication with respect to users who can actually execute the queries.
Krish NAik: For them, we have to pass. So it means that, first of all, I say that this is the tool that I need. Then, who can run that tool? It's not like that everybody can run that tool.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, based on that, I have passed the access groups. So, by default, it comes as, like, admin at the right example.com, or user at the right example.com. It can be based on email IDs also.
Krish NAik: Alright, now the tools are done. Now, this is the user resolver, okay, where you have to pass your authentication and permission. Okay, now this class, directly, I've taken it from the documentation, if you look into. So, for, so right now, I'm just creating a user. Through this user, I'll be accessing the database.
Krish NAik: what is the ID of the user, the email, and you can see the group membership. So, this is full access. So, previously, only two users, the user and the admin, the same membership that I am passing. It means that the new user that I am
Krish NAik: Creating and putting it inside this particular group.
Krish NAik: Okay, and once the user is ready, so I'll be doing the initialization of the user. Now, this is much more an agentic framework, so the approach will be a little bit agent-ic. If you guys know a little bit about, like, like, it's not very similar to Langra app, a little bit with respect to Creeway, I can say, to some prospect.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the user authentication, and this, everybody has to do. It means that according to your original documentation only, so for example, if I do… okay, so this is the user authentication part.
Krish NAik: Okay, once the authentication is done, finally the agent initialization that will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: Okay, so as we have done, in the next step, we'll be having the agent initialization.
Krish NAik: So, right here, simply, let me just create the agent, I'll be passing the LLM, I'll be passing the tool, I'll be passing the user, and for now, I'm using the demo agent memory. So, this is an in-memory conversation through which you can access multiple conversations also.
Krish NAik: Multi-turn conversations also. So, multiple things. So, right now, demo agent memory is just like an in-memory conversation history.
Krish NAik: How to get the user details? These are manual. Whatever the things that I have passed, keep it saying. Don't change it.
Krish NAik: Get up.
Krish NAik: Okay? Step 3 and 4, in your case, the user will be same. It means that I'm creating the user, and then I am passing it.
Krish NAik: In your case, also, you'll be creating the user.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I'll be repeating all the steps once again. Everybody, please?
Krish NAik: start from the, first cell. So, the first cell is working for everybody, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, I'm going… repeating myself, so again, that's why.
Krish NAik: Alright, for everybody, it's working fine. Now, in the next step, you have the environment load part, okay? So, let me just restart again, okay? Because, again, reinitialization of certain variables that I have to do.
Krish NAik: So, the first part, then comes loading the environment, pretty much standard boilerplate, then comes your LLM initialization service.
Krish NAik: Then comes your database connection.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, Postgres. Then I'm, creating a tool, okay, and that tool can be accessed. So, in that tool, I'm providing the database connection, as well as what type of user groups can access it.
Krish NAik: Okay, who can access this tool in simple terms?
Krish NAik: This is the registration of the tools. Then comes the user resolver. It means that for this access group that I have passed, there has to be a user who has access to this group. So for that, I'm creating that user, tutorial underscore user. I pass an email for that particular user, and I'm giving the group membership.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the creation of… Create user label.
Krish NAik: Then, in the next step, I am initializing the agent. If you have joined late, then there's nothing I can do.
Krish NAik: Okay? Because this is repeating second time.
Krish NAik: So, this is the part with respect to the agent initialization. Once the user is all… it means that the user authentication is done. In the next step, I'll be initializing my VANA AI agent. Okay? Now, this agent will orchestrate all the components of VANA.
Krish NAik: So, during the agent creation, I'm passing what is the LLM that will be used, what is the tool that will be used, who will be using this particular agent, so user underscore resolver, and finally comes the agent memory.
Krish NAik: Okay, definition, alright.
Krish NAik: Agent memory, yes, it's an in-memory implementation, as simple as that. If you want, you can bring your custom vector databases and you can do that.
Krish NAik: Right now, you have to understand, it's not… I'm teaching you VANA, I'm showing you the core functionalities of VANA that I have used it in the project.
Krish NAik: Okay? That is my main objective. Later on, if you want, you can explore Vana. Vana is really a good one.
Krish NAik: So, now, the first part is, I'm creating a helper function for direct SQL access. It means that
Krish NAik: to fire any queries directly on top of our SQL databases.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: As simple as that, this is for direct
Krish NAik: query firing on top of the DB. Nothing was related to LLM and other things that comes in. So, if you really look into connection to the database.
Krish NAik: This is, like, our previous class that we have done.
Krish NAik: Okay? Satish, please check the notion, the schema is already provided there.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, so everybody see, this is a pure connection, nothing more. A simple connection, nothing related to one of this function. This function will only fire a SQL query, and based on that, whatever is the response, it will get it. Is this part clear?
Krish NAik: Then the return type of the function is a pandas data frame. So that's why I'm doing a readSQL query here, then I'm passing my main SQL object with the connection string.
Krish NAik: Is this part clear?
Krish NAik: Yes, this is only the super-based connection set of direct pandas that I'm using to create the connection, and then finally I will close it. A simple helper function.
Krish NAik: This is nothing AI here, okay? This is simple SQL with pandas and nothing more.
Krish NAik: people who are telling tables got created, I have already shared the SQL file, please go through the EST, I have already pulled that part.
Krish NAik: How many times I have to repeat myself? You have that, where is that file? GitHub, GitHub, GitHub, yes. Inside the data, you have the generate…
Krish NAik: Sample data. Pooh, Vendiram, and others, whoever is asking, table got created, but there is no data. Please check this one.
Krish NAik: You have to execute that file, and based on that… so yesterday, I've already shown you that part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is an helper function with a helper function, okay, so run simple SQL, okay, so this is a simple execution with respect to pandas, nothing with respect to one IEI.IM tool. Simple, direct with.
Krish NAik: Based on that, you will be also getting the results. Please have a check. For example, select star from customers, limit 5, okay, and based on that, I'm getting the table.
Krish NAik: Similarly, you'll be getting the access to the product table, the orders table, so 3 tables I had, a simple operation with respect to pandas, to check the connection is working, and the verification is done.
Krish NAik: you will see the table for sure, because I think for everybody.
Krish NAik: Because I know the table should be shown.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, you can print it sometimes if it is not, because, see, I have a separate function also, display.
Krish NAik: This one. So, this display will actually help you. So, this is a helper function that I have created. So, using this display function only, I'm sure. So, if somebody's getting an error, please check the display function is properly configured, or you might have missed executing that set.
Krish NAik: Display also prints in data frame. Alright, fine, so on. So, others, please let me know for you guys, is it working or not?
Krish NAik: Sampat is telling 184 res value error, port out of range. Just check the port, because see, in the database connection string, everything will be written there.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, working, here's working, yes working, message telling not working, MSS telling table is empty. If you have not added any data into your table, then nothing will get to know.
Krish NAik: See, if there is no data in your table, first of all, do the verification that the data is there or not in your superbase.
Krish NAik: People will say, I'm not getting results, so simply please have it checked from your table editor. Go to the table editor and at least look. You have that data or not. If there is no data, then nothing will be returned. Pretty much simple, I think, if you don't have anything in your table, then what it will return? Nothing for sure.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please have a check that the data is available. For that data, I have already shared the script, this one, generates sample data that you can directly execute. In the last class, I have already told you, if there is no data in your supervis, nothing will be returned.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, people who are getting that, please have a check.
Krish NAik: If they are… if… just be sure, only not the table creation. Inside that table, you'll be populating some data.
Krish NAik: Because few people are telling, they are getting because they have configured, and few people have not done it. Because in the last class, I have already shown that plus, please do the configuration. Sampat is telling port is configured 6543 is… for me, 654… if I check my connection string.
Krish NAik: Again, so it depends upon the connection string, really.
Krish NAik: In my case, it's 5432.
Krish NAik: In your case, like, whichever connection pooling that you are using, based on that. Because my IP connection is IPv6, so I won't be facing any issues. If you have an IPv4, then you can use the transactional puller and basically the session puller. So based on that, please have a check according to your ISP connection.
Krish NAik: Okay? Till now, Raul is selling photos. Okay, please have a check. You guys probably might have an IPv4 from your ISV.
Krish NAik: I have an IPv6, so people having IPv6, they won't be getting any error. So, it's only people with IPv4. So, based on that, use the session puller. According to the documentation, session puller is the best one that you can work with.
Krish NAik: Okay, Saurav, rules are expected all right.
Krish NAik: Okay, Amar Sinivas, mine all steps are executed, great. What about others? People, please let me know. You are getting the output, because this is simple SQL execution, nothing with related to AI that I have done till now.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Few people are stuck. See, people might be… get stuck. One is due to the connection issue with your superbase. You need to resolve that. If you don't have IPv6, nothing that I can do. You need to configure that, okay, according to IPv4, session puller is your best option. So, please use that.
Krish NAik: Again, I am repeating, please use the session puller, don't use the direct connection string, it's generally for IPv6.
Krish NAik: Okay, session puller, transaction puller, both of them supports IPv4. Okay? Alright. Now, then just be sure your API key is correct.
Krish NAik: That is the only requirement.
Krish NAik: The database should be available, okay, at least in your tables, just have to check the data. If there is no data, nothing that we can do.
Krish NAik: Balaji, please check the documentation. Previously, already, we have discussed how to set up the session puller part.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, okay. Now, this is a simple query directly, I'm passing it to the function. Okay, so the another way, because this query was small, this time, a multi-line query that I am executing. So, from here also, you'll be getting the result.
Krish NAik: PA is asking from where I can find this data. It is inside the data folder PA.
Krish NAik: Today's schema is different, no? Today's schema, already it's there in the Notion.
Krish NAik: See, the schema is only different. So, this schema I've already shared in the Notion, guys. Please check Notion.
Krish NAik: If you use yesterday's schema, that schema is different, and this schema is different.
Krish NAik: Okay? Alright.
Krish NAik: It's there in the repo as well. I know it's there in the repo, but in the Notion also, directly, if you want to do the copy-paste, in whichever way you do it, just be sure you are doing it.
Krish NAik: Okay? Somewhere, if you have messed it, fine, you can do it, but the idea is that if everything is… the connection is done, it should be up and working. See, simply, if you have created what you can do, create a new project. People who have used the old schema, go to, your superbase, here, organization, just create a new project.
Krish NAik: Okay, yesterday I created this one, all text-to-SQL, if you remember.
Krish NAik: Okay? So just go and create a new project. Don't delete or do any. Just create a new project, it will be better in your case.
Krish NAik: Okay, whoever has used the wrong schema. For them, I am suggesting.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, okay, now, providing the schema documentation to the agent. Now, this is the most important step. So, generally, the schema context.
Krish NAik: this entire schema context that I'll be passing it in one shot later on, because through this, only the LLM takes the decision. Now, this is actually a powerful thing, very similar to your SQL query retriever in Llama Index.
Krish NAik: But in Llama Index, I feel that you had that added when you, like, you have that added benefit of selecting those tables, because every table you can pass in context. And during the query, you don't need all the tables.
Krish NAik: So, your, the LLM, the actual prompt that goes, it becomes much smaller and much more optimized. You don't need to pass the entire…
Krish NAik: I can say, context, or the schema context. So, there, optimization can be done, but here, at least a high level, entire context that needs to be passed. So, based on the tables, I had 3 tables. What is the schema? If you look into, then comes your product.
Krish NAik: Then I have written my orders, then I have passed what type of relationship. Okay, so one-to-many relationship.
Krish NAik: These I have passed.
Krish NAik: So this is my main schema that I'll be passing it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just like last time, a very similar implementation, here it is a little bit different.
Krish NAik: Okay, Santosh is telling Shared Puller also giving IPv4. IPv4…
Krish NAik: Really, like, guys, you were stuck into that IPv4 connection?
Krish NAik: Then how will you do that part? Hmm?
Krish NAik: That's why I told, like, yesterday, I know that connection issue can be there, so you should…
Krish NAik: Just spend some time, because I know the connection will be there, you know, for sure. Some type of param issue, that can be one major thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please have a check, Santosh, on that.
Krish NAik: Because till now, only the SQL part, and this is a part with respect to the schema context elimination according to the tables that I have. Only that part I have done. Till now, I have not started VANA execution, nothing with respect to VANA that I have executed.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, people, please have it checked with respect to your params of your connection string. If there is some error, for sure. So, first of all, check the connection is working using the script that I have shared, this one. Okay, the superbasecontest.py.
Krish NAik: If this works, then only the other things will work. If here only it fails, nothing that we can do. Okay, we need to fix the first, the connection strip.
Krish NAik: Alright, Mitesh, you have changed each config value separately. Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Generally, people having IPv6, no issue. Only with V4, you might get the issue.
Krish NAik: And I think a lot of ISPs are still now using V4 only.
Krish NAik: Satish, I cannot let you know exactly, like, why you are getting there.
Krish NAik: If the schema is different, you will be getting the error with respect to SQL.
Krish NAik: As simple as that.
Krish NAik: Special characters are not allowed in the password.
Krish NAik: In my password, I think I have at the rate, one at the rate is there.
Krish NAik: No, because again, I don't remember that thing, but I feel that I have, that in my DB URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if I show you this one…
Krish NAik: Okay, actually, no, I don't have anything here. That is that, name, actually.
Krish NAik: So just remove any special characters if you are using it in the password.
Krish NAik: Yeah, everybody.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me know, can I proceed to the next part?
Krish NAik: Yes? Alright, let's proceed then.
Krish NAik: Now, as the context is ready, this entire thing is inside a simple variable. Later on, I'll be passing this schema context during our LLM call.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, let's do the query of the agent. See, I'll be having multiple functions to show you, actually, what is the output of VANA. In VANA, everything is based on async. It means that all the execution, it has to be, like, an asynchronous operations.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, I need a request context. Okay, now, through this, actually, I'll be making the HTTP request.
Krish NAik: Then, like, how many customers? Now, this is a test query that I am passing.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, the return type of the request context, there will be multiple components, because it has an UI thing inside that. Okay? So, because of that UI thing, a lot of things that will be shown, so don't get confused, I will show you exactly how to access it.
Krish NAik: Now, the first thing…
Krish NAik: that you have for UI in component in agent.sendMessage. So, when you actually print out send message, there are a lot of components. UI components are there.
Krish NAik: Now, we will be accessing each component one by one, and then we'll be printing it, okay? So, let me just execute.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now you will see that, one by one, this will take some time.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the execution will start.
Krish NAik: So, how many customers are there in the databases? Okay, so if you really look into, in the output, somewhere you'll be getting some answer, because so many components are there. Can you see your content? There are 100 customers in the database.
Krish NAik: Now, you need to access that component, and based on that, you need to, throw out the result.
Krish NAik: Okay? These are all UI-based components.
Krish NAik: Okay, Ankit Ashley, I got it fixed from the agent, alright, Ankit? Please let me know, guys, are you getting the response? You should be getting the response.
Krish NAik: And the last component.
Krish NAik: This is pure text-to-SQL.
Krish NAik: No rag till now. Nothing with respect to RAG.
Krish NAik: Generally, I integrate with my RAG system, like in this project I have done.
Krish NAik: Is this a streaming response? No. Just for a small thing.
Krish NAik: This entire thing that you are getting, okay?
Krish NAik: this entire thing is based on UI components, so multiple components are there, okay? Now, out of that, I'm just showing you. Here, also, you can see.
Krish NAik: This is the query result. Okay, so here you can see the SQL query returned 1 rows with one column, so row count.
Krish NAik: That entire thing, searchable, sortable, other things that it actually picked up. So, you will be getting the answer, so you have to actually access it. Later on, I'll be telling you how to access the component, because these are all reach-based components, and we'll be accessing each of the components.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, this is the return type of a 1AI region. So, when you look into, yes, it looks
Krish NAik: complex, but from there, we'll be accessing. So this is the main component type text through which you can access the result.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, this is the main output of the agent, and later on, I'll be doing parsing on top of the output.
Krish NAik: Till now, I have not passed the schema. This is direct, without the schema. I'm showing you, without the schema also, it works.
Krish NAik: Now, next king, here, okay, so… As you can see here, This time.
Krish NAik: I will be passing the schema. In the last time, I didn't pass the schema context, okay? So here, with a simple condition, include Boolean, I've created a function, do you want to pass it? You can make it true or false, and you can always have a check on that. By default, it is true.
Krish NAik: Now, see, previously, we have been defined… doing the same thing. We created our request context, okay? And this time, I'll be doing a parsing. Okay, it means that once I send the message to the agent, from there, I'm extracted. Now, this is a simple parsing operation.
Krish NAik: Okay, from the component. So you have to actually look into the output, and based on that, you have to do the parsing. So here, I'm actually looking for… I am handling something with respect to data frames also, just to show you the output in a better way.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, this is a function that I have. Okay, this is with explanations, later on I'll be executing it, okay? Now, let me execute this one. Now, this will be a much more cleaner outlook.
Krish NAik: For you guys to understand.
Krish NAik: Okay, so previously, the output, a lot of things were there. From there, I have done a simple parsing.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Because out of so many components, I have picked up exactly what is the component, which is component-rich. Through that, I am actually accessing it. Is this part clear?
Krish NAik: what I have done. It's actually the same thing.
Krish NAik: the same thing that I have done, but what I have done this time, a simple parsing, and even I have appended my schema context. That is the only thing. Now.
Krish NAik: If I, don't want… so, if you want a better way, okay, so what I will do, let me just, comment this entire one, okay? So, just one comment.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this one I will uncomment.
Krish NAik: So, yes. Now, here, I've kept the explanation also, because for the AI agent, you can also get the explanation. So, for example, how many customers we do have?
Krish NAik: This time, you'll be getting some explanation. We have a total of 100 users. If you want the explanation, that is all available also inside the component. If you want to get the explainability at any point of time, what the agent is through.
Krish NAik: Sometimes the agent might be, confused also, so it will simply say that, yes, that I am confused, okay, and because of that, it won't show you the query.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'm showing you with the explanation, in whichever way you want to execute it, I have kept both the parsing functions. Okay, so one for getting the main data frame component, and then you have the text explanation. From the agent, these things are returned.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, for example, an aggregation query, what is the total revenue from all the orders?
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, as you can see, the question, based on the schema, the final order things, 8 into 44 columns, query result, the total revenue from all the orders, okay, this is the explanation of text that you have.
Krish NAik: Similarly, you can execute the other queries, please let me know, are you guys getting it? So, if you want the explanation, just be sure. So, you have
Krish NAik: the functions with the both names. AsyncDepth, okay, and here also this asyncDepth agent, whichever agent that you want to pass it.
Krish NAik: Just be sure in the second one, I have not passed any schema context here, if you look into. And this is one with the schema context. So, simple, two things that I have differed.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you really look into… in the explanation part, I am not passing any schema context. In the other function, I have kept it. So, whichever function, if you feel to need the… that you need the explanation part, you can use the below function, or if you don't need the explanation, use the above function.
Krish NAik: So, totally up to you.
Krish NAik: MS is asking from where Vana is accessing the DB credentials?
Krish NAik: From here, step 2, initialize the PostgreSQL runner.
Krish NAik: R is asking what is the difference between passing the schema context? So, generally, if you pass the schema context, okay, so the response will be better. If you have more and more tables in that case, if you have lesser number of tables within your database, then you really do need to pass that.
Krish NAik: Generally, for complex queries, it is much better to pass your schema context, but without the schema context also, it works.
Krish NAik: In my case, yes, the number of customers is 100.
Krish NAik: Because, the fake data that I have generated… okay, so from there.
Krish NAik: Guys, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Is the executions working for everybody?
Krish NAik: Working, barrage, alright. Total of 140 orders have been delivered.
Krish NAik: Join query, okay, show me the top 5 customers by total spending.
Krish NAik: Alright, customer ID, okay, and this is the explanation that is coming. These are great. Group by join, okay, what is the average order value for each customer segment?
Krish NAik: So, always remember that particular function, you need to configure it once, it's always better. Okay, and this is your final query results, it looks like.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if it gets confused, it simply tells that, okay? So, for example, in this case, it's telling that, okay, the orders table does not contain a customer segment, it only includes a field like ID, customer ID. So, detailed explanation you get. So, we need to find out how customer segments are classified.
Krish NAik: So, the entire process through which it will… could you confirm if there is a separate table on that?
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, I'm not building a conversational bot, but this is the return type.
Krish NAik: Now, show orders from me for the last 30 days. So, if you directly look into, I feel that this is much better as directly working with Lama and others. It gives much more direct powerful.
Krish NAik: And all these conversations, whichever I'm doing, you will see that these will be saved here, inside your query results. Guys, please check that inside the notebook folder, one, these files will be created.
Krish NAik: Yes, for every question, you'll be getting charged for sure.
Krish NAik: Because for every call, you'll be calling the tool.
Krish NAik: And the tool will call the LLMR again, that's why.
Krish NAik: Now, Mantage is asking.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mantas, can you use these agents for data generation, which can further be used for testing? Yes, from the output of the, like, SQL agent, you can pass that to another agent for further generation.
Krish NAik: Alright, what is the… I think 3 types of customers we that I had.
Krish NAik: Based on that, okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, in simple cases, sometimes it throws you error. I won't say that every time it works very good.
Krish NAik: Okay, but finally, like, it takes time through multiple explanations, okay, because here, even feedback loops are directly available in VANA.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that, enterprise customers are also coming.
Krish NAik: So, I can see that, yes, if it gets confused, it is able to come out of that through feedback loops of internal voila, and it can do. So, rectification, this is really good. So, it is an agent-to-based framework, not a direct framework. So, yes, these features are
Krish NAik: Every and every agent, they have a…
Krish NAik: Self-healing loop, okay? Or a self-feedback loop, that sort.
Krish NAik: Alright, now coming to the context part. Now, this is the where… okay, so if you remember, include schema is equal to false. Okay, so you can simply change this if you remember the function. Now, that function, actually, I have changed it, because I have been showing you everything with respect to the explanation.
Krish NAik: And if you change this, and if you use the other function, the other function is much better, and it will give you better results as compared to, this function, the second one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, I'll be just commenting everything, okay?
Krish NAik: And let me get this one.
Krish NAik: Ctrl-a, all it.
Krish NAik: Yeah, now, this function I have executed, okay, so here you have the schema context also.
Krish NAik: Now, if I'm taking a vote, if something got…
Krish NAik: Confused, okay? So let me check that part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so from here also, like, here, if you look into the final explanation, though it throwed me the result, now, let me just execute. Because on the second part, I've not kept the
Krish NAik: part with respect to the explanation. So here, you won't be getting the explanation, but you'll be getting the output.
Krish NAik: So, here, the average order value. Can you see here, you've gotten better output with the schema context?
Krish NAik: Previously, the schema context was not available, but this time, yes, based on the multiple segments that I have.
Krish NAik: inside my database, ESS scrolling. So, it's always a good practice, you can include both, because I have provided you both the functions, you can make it a single one, that it will be using the schema context, as well as if you want to access the explanations also.
Krish NAik: Alright, now…
Krish NAik: So, based on this simple parameter, so if I make it false.
Krish NAik: Okay, now see, include schema is equal to false, I have kept it. Then, also, you will see, you'll be getting the result. The total revenue is coming close to $34,6189.
Krish NAik: Okay? Now, with the schema.
Krish NAik: Okay, again, it's not like that you will be getting, but I feel that when you have more and more tables, complex queries, okay, in that case, having the schema context is really good.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, without the schema context, also, it works, but… the…
Krish NAik: Failing condition, I feel that more than 30-40% of the times, if you have something as a complex query, it will fail.
Krish NAik: Yes, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Then, at any point of time, if you feel that you need to do the verification.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want to do the verification, you can pass by the custom SQL condition which has been generated. Okay, so, like, this is just for verification whether the agent is giving you the correct result or not.
Krish NAik: REM is telling my total revenue showed zero when include schema was false.
Krish NAik: Alright, I don't think it should be directly 0.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because, in my case, without the schema also, it's working. Same here.
Krish NAik: Okay, RNS link, but when I ran again, it showed fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, just try to run again, because sometimes there's an agent call. Generally, there should not be any mistake, but have a check. Because in my case, I'm not getting zero, and others are also telling that they are not getting zero, only one or two person is telling.
Krish NAik: Generally, Murta, for, handling long schemas, okay? Now, if you really look into the concept of prompt catching, OpenAI models don't support that, okay? Anthropic models support that. In that case, generally for, implementing any type of, like, prompt catching concept, I work with anthropic-based models.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is much better. Otherwise, in VANA, then I will go ahead with the Lama Index SQL retriever, because there you have that get user info tables. Okay, based on the query, first it will look into the tables, and only the context of those tables will be passed. So if you have 1,000 tables.
Krish NAik: And based on the query, you need to look into only 5 tables. So I know the context of 5 tables will be passed. So that is the way of optimization in Llama Index, which can be done. Here, it's, rather than passing that entire context in one shot.
Krish NAik: Can you give? No, Lama Index is different, Vana is different, Matej. Don't confuse.
Krish NAik: Okay? Both the things are totally different. You can't mix Lama Index and VANA.
Krish NAik: Holding.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a direct SQL firing query, okay, just to do the check.
Krish NAik: Then, okay, some other questions, how many products are in stock? Okay, based on that, you'll be getting aggregation queries, few more queries and queries that I have kept.
Krish NAik: Because this… in a similar way in our application, I'll be creating the agent, and I'll be making the call, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and some others, like, okay, generally, like,
Krish NAik: Keeping ambiguous questions is not a… it's, like, a very bad practice. For example, show me all the customers from the website.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, ES8 works, but it's a bad practice, always remember.
Krish NAik: Incorrect column names, it can create a problem.
Krish NAik: Okay, but the agent tries to fix it.
Krish NAik: But if you parse the schema context, okay, so generally, agent, if it makes any mistake, always through feedback loops, it will try to do the rectification. But it is always better to pass your schema context.
Krish NAik: Because in your schema, what is the table name? Through that only you will get. Otherwise, every time it has to access it.
Krish NAik: And if somebody writes something wrong, okay, and probably if you have table, like, revenue underscore 1 and revenue underscore 2, it might get confused.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is the other one.
Krish NAik: Then, case sensitivity, this is also another issue. So, generally, based on the column names, this can create a problem. Okay, show delivered orders, so generally we have to look into the status.
Krish NAik: How many orders have been delivered?
Krish NAik: Now, here you can see the response. Now, these are the final orders which have been delivered.
Krish NAik: So, you can actually look into entirely. So, I feel that this is much better as compared to Llama Intex, because really you don't need a RAG.
Krish NAik: So, text-to-SQL VC agents are much good. Anybody who has worked with VANA.ai previously, Yes, anybody who has worked?
Krish NAik: Because I know you guys work with Text2SQL, but nobody has worked.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine.
Krish NAik: Okay. Because, see, I'm giving you a starting point. From now, you can explore more and more. Fauna is really good.
Krish NAik: with SQLAlchemy only, alright, fine. Hard the first time this class.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, now see, from this particular tracker, always remember.
Krish NAik: accessing… here you have more and more information. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Generally, it's a good practice to look into all the logs here, exactly what is coming, okay? Because finally, we can get the result through the… always create a custom function, and whatever the information that you want to parse it, okay, you can, because I have done only two levels of parsing, the text variable and the explanation one.
Krish NAik: Okay? But if you guys want to, get more, so you can actually look into the return type. I feel, majorly, I've taken the count, the results have text, information, but…
Krish NAik: This is a simple and a much more powerful tool.
Krish NAik: Legacy 1.0 was much harder to do the setup, but in 2.0, they have made it completely an agent-based framework.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so this was the cool thing, and now this particular integration, we'll be doing it directly in our RAG application, okay? In our RAG application, we'll be creating a hybrid router.
Krish NAik: just to check, okay, so if somebody passed a query, it will automatically detect, okay, where to throw that query, based on keyword logic that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: simply a routing mechanism that I have kept, and based on that, it means that if something that comes based on… if it is detected as a query, it will be calling vana.ai. But if it is something detected as a direct document-based query, then it will go to the vector DB index.
Krish NAik: So, a simple querying mechanism.
Krish NAik: Satish, the wire is telling running out, operational could not translate, db.
Krish NAik: NemoService. This is your database connection error, Satish. Please have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Alright, for how many of you, everything worked successfully in this particular notebook, please let me know in the chats.
Krish NAik: Okay? Worked, worked, worked.
Krish NAik: Everything.
Krish NAik: Alright, yeah, Subhash, correct.
Krish NAik: Alright, people who are getting DB connection fail, I think if you spend some time, it will be sorted out. Really, like, it's not in my hand. You have to fix your own connection issue. Because I feel that directly I passed it, so based on your IPv4 or IPv6, please check that part.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, so majorly, it's working. I can see a few people are telling connection issues, connection issues. Please have a check on that.
Krish NAik: SK is telling there are 5 tables… 5 tables? I don't think there are 5 tables, there are only 3 tables. I know. SK, please have a check.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, SK was telling you, if you have created a table context, find with 1000 tables also. You can pass it. The context window, you can use a bigger LLM.
Krish NAik: somehow, some type of, like, prompt compression that can be done. Okay, so in that way, little bit of…
Krish NAik: Like, other concepts are there. Pruning we can apply. If you have 10,000, 1 million tables also, that is possible.
Krish NAik: Swarab Burma, okay, alright, incorrect column name. Have a check on that, just check that with context, because during the explanation, I'm not doing any context.
Krish NAik: SK was asking how to create the context.
Krish NAik: There are multiple ways, so right now, I have just shown you the simple one.
Krish NAik: Because there are other concepts, like context screening, context optimization, context completion, through those things we can do.
Krish NAik: Arian, are there any metrics to check the accuracy of the answer? Generally, yes, they have spider-based metrics, but it is a bit different, because right now I'm directly not working, this is much more agent-based framework. So here, generally, the generated query, you can actually have a check.
Krish NAik: Okay, the query there. And most of the times, you know that the queries can be different, but the output can be seen.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we have to use some type of logic through which it can be checked. So, here, direct RAG-level metrics are not available.
Krish NAik: All right, fine, let's go for a break, okay, and then we will start with the application part.
Krish NAik: SK is asking, please show how you created the table product context so that we can
Krish NAik: How I have created, it's simple. The table information, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: There is nothing fancy. Please go and look into that schema context variable. I've already passed that, and I've shown.
Krish NAik: In this notebook, just see, this is a simple, based on the table and the column information that I am passing.
Krish NAik: If you want to keep some other information, table description, those things also, you can keep it.
Krish NAik: Yes, Mudassar, you can use Landsmith. I think you were talking about Landsmith? Yes, you can do the integration with Landsmith.
Krish NAik: PA, can we make LLM here to clarify with the user in case of ambiguity? Yes, you can add another call, an LLM verification call, like LLM as a judge, you can add it, for sure.
Krish NAik: This is not like docstring. This is docstring, but this is entirely in a variable. Generally, we create a separate file, like schema underscore context, and we read that file.
Krish NAik: But I thought, keep… let's keep it as a variable here.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: This is a simple variable.
Krish NAik: This is a list of table columns and the data types, correct? That's the only thing.
Krish NAik: That's the only thing I'm passing it into the context.
Krish NAik: Alright. Fine guys, so let's go for a break.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, people, just be sure you are correct, selected the correct schema and the correct database.
Krish NAik: Modhasar is asking, why not pull this context form DB, like, description for DB? Why not pull from where you will be pulling that information? If you have certain information in a table, then only you can do that.
Krish NAik: For complex, yeah, it's just working, DDL…
Krish NAik: When you use DDL, we add description to the columns, alright, in that way. Through DDL, actually, through DDL, you can do multiple training and other things also in one adult day.
Krish NAik: No, right now, that is not my focus, Rabi USA. You can explode that.
Krish NAik: I've taken an agent-based approach, not a NL to SQL approach.
Krish NAik: Let me take a timer. Guys, let me know 10 minutes, okay? Let me start the timer.
Krish NAik: Everything is there in the code widget.
Krish NAik: Please have a look into the quote, at least.
Krish NAik: Okay, a few people are working with respect to bench.
Krish NAik: Because in text-to-SQL, the metrics are totally different as well.
Krish NAik: You have… EX and others one. I'll be sharing that one particular document that I have.
Krish NAik: Generally, like, SPIDER is a dataset through which you do the benchmarking, but you have to look into the execution, accuracy, the exact match, the success rate, so a few metrics and protocols are there.
Krish NAik: Thanks, so guys, just be back in time so that we can now continue with our discussion with respect to the application part.
Krish NAik: Vijay, you don't have to do anything.
Krish NAik: Just check the notebook, there is a variable called as the schemaContext.
Krish NAik: Yes, MongoDB configuration, Sharantijay, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Generally, it's for SQL, they say, text to SQL.
Krish NAik: It's not like text to no SQL, you have to understand that. Majorly, the task that we are doing is based on SQL.
Krish NAik: Yes, it can be different. It's not deterministic, Satish.
Krish NAik: People, please have a check with respect to your connection strength, rather than asking me, because here, nothing I can do. Yesterday, already I have shown that part. It's the same thing that you need to do it from your site.
Krish NAik: Accept the database statistics. Alright, generally it should work, database stats also, not sure exactly why it's not there.
Krish NAik: Check that later on during the doubts, I will look into those things.
Krish NAik: Alright, because there are a lot of issues, also open issues in Ghana, things are getting solved. But right now, just like last year.
Krish NAik: Till this phase, okay, so a lot of things have become very much stable.
Krish NAik: Still no bugs are there.
Krish NAik: In today's one, I'm using a connection string, Raja. Okay, so please have a check. I'm not using multiple environment variables, like, like last time.
Krish NAik: So, the older one is different, this one is different.
Krish NAik: Yes, it is available in the UI components. When they run through that, you can access it.
Krish NAik: What are the approaches for VANA, other than agentic approach?
Krish NAik: VANA is completely agent-to-framework.
Krish NAik: There are no other approaches, only the agentic approaches there in Vana.
Krish NAik: Probably.
Krish NAik: Okay, Balaji Rangam is telling, got connection issue resolved by session puller. I told you session puller, that's why. For IPv4, it is the suggested one.
Krish NAik: Alright, Modhasar, you have used load underscore dot ENV override is equal to true to make the new connection work. Alright.
Krish NAik: Yes, generally for IPv4 guys, session puller is the best. I do have an IPv6 with me, so in that case.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's open source.
Krish NAik: Obi chic.
Krish NAik: Where can I update the connection config you were asking?
Krish NAik: Connection config, I'm not sure, because complex nested SQL status file, For analytical functions…
Krish NAik: Because really, I have not checked a lot with this VANA. Based on, like, BI tools, I've not done that particular use case.
Krish NAik: You can explore that route.
Krish NAik: Yes, Agent TKI will start, like, once we complete Haystack Monthasar, like, after Project 2, we will be discussing Project 3, then we will discuss Haystack, then Langrap will start.
Krish NAik: I meant the new course. There is no new course right now, with respect to courses there, only project discussion will happen.
Krish NAik: Not, teaching a technology, rather than those are just projects.
Krish NAik: because the new agent course will come in March, I think.
Krish NAik: And then the RAG and LLM course that I will be taking, it'll be coming in the month of… end of May.
Krish NAik: Okay, that is my timeline, because your batch will be completed by the first week of April or by second week.
Krish NAik: Agentic 3.0, yes, it will be coming in March, second week or third week.
Krish NAik: My inconcerting will be, in that agentic one.
Krish NAik: I've taken Agentic 1.0, but really, like, I'm not a fan of agents.
Krish NAik: I'm much more into that research part, so I'll be taking LLMs and RAC. In the next RAC batch, I'll be including LLM fine-tuning and a lot of other things.
Krish NAik: Duration of Agentic 3? Agentic badges are generally 5 months.
Krish NAik: 5 to 6 months max.
Krish NAik: Deep learning, Gen AI, yes, that is the new batch that got launched, no, I think, last week. UDS is there.
Krish NAik: There, I'll be teaching that deep learning part. GenAI fundamentals are only there. LLM batch will be different. In the next RAC batch, I'll be upgrading that batch with, like, custom fine-tuning, domain-specific data fine-tuning, SLM fine-tuning, those type of topics, I'll be keeping it with the RAC.
Krish NAik: The entire RAG thing, few things I will remove, actually. Like, data parsers module, I will remove it. Probably one module only I will discuss, so few optimizations that I'll be doing.
Krish NAik: Albright.
Krish NAik: How do we know your batches? It will be launched. Live batches are less only in a year maximum, because
Krish NAik: Our mentor limit is pretty much less, like…
Krish NAik: Probably, I think, because LLM ops won't be launched, so I know in the new agent patch, it will be, like, Sunny and Mike.
Krish NAik: there, they will be taking. Because I am not really into so much agents, really. Because I feel,
Krish NAik: I've worked with Langraph, Agnew, and Creve AI, but really.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, it's wrapping up functions within a particular agent only. It means that I'll be defining a tool, and that tool becomes a custom function. So, very less R&Ds, yeah.
Krish NAik: Alright, now… Alright, the timer is done. I think 10 minutes timer, I will stop it.
Krish NAik: It's not possible, I can take only 2 batches for me, probably. I don't know, like, for RAG, Advanced Batch, if you require…
Krish NAik: Because I feel the number of students who will be coming into that RAC batch.
Krish NAik: Okay, because one fresh batch, and if you want from your batch a very specialized topic that needs to be discussed.
Krish NAik: then I can take an extension only for this batch field students I can pick up who are really interested. So I have to really check the count and the number of students. Then you guys can focus that on advanced rank.
Krish NAik: Because there are a lot of things in RAG. Like, RAG has its own depth, it's just like an ocean, when you actually try to explore it in depth.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: I think this is my desktop 3, let me start sharing, okay? So, this notebook is done, I will close it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now…
Krish NAik: Everybody, the notebook execution is done. Okay, so now we will start with the application. First, we will test the application that in your system it is working on.
Krish NAik: Okay? Later on, I will create everything from scratch, but initially do the testing, that in your system, it is up and working.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for example, what you can do, in the mainENV.example file, okay, there are other things also. Okay, you can do the configuration, because I think the Opening API key, that is fine, the database URL.
Krish NAik: then just be sure you are passing your Pinecone API key, the Pinecone environment, I think you are using by default, US East 1, AWS, the name of the index.
Krish NAik: for Pinecone, okay?
Krish NAik: Database URL, you guys already have this information with you. Opic part, you can skip it for now. Today's… you can keep it blank, okay? Not a necessary thing.
Krish NAik: Then, VANA configuration, okay, so keep it like this, only the same thing that I have kept for which model, what is the namespace in VANA that will be created with the index.
Krish NAik: Keep same settings like me. Don't change anything. Text chunking, I've used lesser chunk size this time, 512 with a 50 overlap, and a few common settings with respect to applications, okay? Actually, I'm not using this one, so don't get confused by this one, okay? I will just comment it for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just be sure in your env.example file, whatever the things are there, you have it.
Krish NAik: Then, the next step, I'll be testing the application. To start our application.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once you have done the configuration, the command is simply that UVCon command that you will be passing, UV
Krish NAik: con app main appreload, okay? So, right now, reload is for development stages, so simply, or without the reload also, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody just be sure, because right now I'll be just testing the FastlyPay application.
Krish NAik: AWS agents, instead of… AWS agents, instead of VAN, VAN, that is different, like…
Krish NAik: Generally, if I will be using AWS, I'll be hosting completely VANA in AWS.
Krish NAik: in AWS, there are not such services which are highly specialized for text-to-SQL amounts for AWS.
Krish NAik: Okay, so guys, please do the configuration, okay, and then try to start. If there are some errors, you will get it into the logs, so nothing to worry about.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please do that.
Krish NAik: Okay, huh… Okay, I'm using other new courses are not short, right?
Krish NAik: And right.
Krish NAik: I'll take.
Krish NAik: Yes, this is a common bottleneck, Pratmish. You will be passing that huge con… see, generally, right now, in VANA, you have to pass the entire context, but in Lama index, you have that level of optimization, where only you select the table. Because with every table definition, you can pass that context, so it becomes much more optimized, Pratmish.
Krish NAik: Okay, so guys, so everybody, just have a check on the configuration.
Krish NAik: Here, what command do you need to run? The most common EVCon command. This command, everyone, please remember. EVCon, app, main app, so based on my configuration, I think somewhere in your README file, also, I might have kept things, really. I've not gone…
Krish NAik: through that README file in detail, but I think you will be having most of the things
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, if you go, check.
Krish NAik: Okay? What are the things that I have UVCon? So, the command is here for running the application. Just copy-paste that command.
Krish NAik: Okay, hand start.
Krish NAik: Then definitely we can't pass, you can pass.
Krish NAik: Whenever… before you were doing the retrieval, you have to select that one.
Krish NAik: In Llama Index, SQL Retriever, that option is there. OPKPI key, right now, it is not necessary. Next class, otherwise, simply create, it takes only 2 minutes. OP creating an OPKI key.
Krish NAik: If we want, otherwise, OPIC, I'll be discussing in the next class. Right now, requirement of OPIC is not there.
Krish NAik: Alright, non-technical person would get this, really, like, text-to-SQL, nobody, non-technical guy will do this.
Krish NAik: Because really, with respect to the technicality, yes, there are a lot of things that can be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the command, please get it, okay, and try to execute and see everything is up and working.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, in my case, if I start the application.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, majorly all the initialization service that I have done.
Krish NAik: Alright, you'll be getting all the logs. If there is any error, you can, look into that part.
Krish NAik: So, right now, if I go to my… this one, okay, so I will just try to do a reload here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you will be seeing this slash docs for sure.
Krish NAik: Okay? You will be getting your slash drops. By default, FastAPI runs on the port 8000, so you will be looking into that.
Krish NAik: Okay, a lot of other information that I might have, let me delete it, because I have to show you multiple functionalities.
Krish NAik: Test, I think, inside data.
Krish NAik: Stitch.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys, the application started or not. Santosh, working, do I need to change anything before running the UV command? Just be sure about the environment files. Only that thing I'm worried about.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: If you don't have the environment files, okay, so simply we'll be getting that error.
Krish NAik: Alright, working, fine. Let's start.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this app is, the simplest version. Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, you can do a health check, okay? So, check out all the APIs that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here you will see that the major initializations. In your case, some things might be false if you have not done the initialization, but you'll be getting some results, something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay? Some services can be false, it's fine, but at least the major services, like the embedding service, vector service, the RAT service, the SQL service, this should be true.
Krish NAik: Those are app-related. My fast API app details, biology.
Krish NAik: When I create any app, I can create my app details here. So those are those app-related environment files.
Krish NAik: Can you share your environment file? I've already shared the environment file, please have it checked.
Krish NAik: Guys, please have it checked with respect to the environment file where I have that.
Krish NAik: Here, I think. It got hired. Please check the .env example, already provided that. Every time I provide this one.
Krish NAik: Okay. Just be sure you have done the configuration, if you have not done the configuration correctly, okay, you will be getting error.
Krish NAik: Just be sure, okay. Because, see, in my cases, what are the indexes that I have created? So, one… okay, so here, first of all, look into this particular case. So, let's go into the default one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I have two indexes here, one for VANA. Actually, this index, I have not…
Krish NAik: I'm not using it right now in my solution, but I have kept a check. Later on, I'm planning to do a SQL training as a feature. Later on, I will add it. But for now, like, two things. So, similarly, like, this check is also there in your initial app startup. So, I've kept all the checks.
Krish NAik: If something is not available, that service will not start only, okay? So, in your case also, you can create this syntax and keep it.
Krish NAik: This information you have in your config.yme file.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is one requirement. Other than that, I don't think any other major requirements, because…
Krish NAik: My env file, if I show you simply… okay, so… see, all my configurations are there.
Krish NAik: If you really look into, this is my configuration, so just be sure you guys have your own configuration.
Krish NAik: Entirely set up.
Krish NAik: If you have… if there is some issue, you will be getting that error.
Krish NAik: Please show the docs page, okay? Docs page, yes, this is how…
Krish NAik: For me, everything is enabled. Okay, so in your case, some service might not be enabled. And later on, you can switch it there.
Krish NAik: How many of you are getting, like, at least more than these things? OPIC, it will be configured as fault, for sure, you guys have not done it. Database configuration, I know you guys have done it. Pinecone, you have done it. OpenAI, you have done it.
Krish NAik: These services, by default, it comes true, because the initialization happens with document track, text to SQL, and query routing.
Krish NAik: Okay, now if these services are not enabled, then automatically this embedding service cannot be switched on. Okay, so please have a check on that.
Krish NAik: Opic is false, fine. OPIC is false. If you add the opaque API key, it will become, true.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now, Okay, this is…
Krish NAik: Some system information, I have kept it. Actually, this was some Lambda test that I was doing, okay? So, multiple phase-wise testing when I try to do it, okay? So, you really don't need this API right now.
Krish NAik: Okay, get stats API, okay, the type of documents…
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, I don't have any type of documents into the system.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why the total uploaded size, everything is zero, pretty much a blank vector DB that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, then leave the root one. The root is not required, okay? Now, probably uploading a document. Now, this is the part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me test this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… let me choose a file…
Krish NAik: I think somewhere I'll be having some…
Krish NAik: PDF, texture SQL, I think from here, from data.
Krish NAik: Docs.
Krish NAik: Not here also.
Krish NAik: Because I think I can upload this one.
Krish NAik: This is okay… this is a different one.
Krish NAik: Just pass any PDF for now. That is the main thing. You can pass attention is all you need, also paper for now.
Krish NAik: Anything that you want.
Krish NAik: just be sure you are passing one PDF, okay? And pick up something small, don't use something big, because the embedding cost will come with the OpenAI.
Krish NAik: But I think I have kept it context flat, text-tooth.
Krish NAik: Basic one data.
Krish NAik: These two days.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please have a check on this one, whether it's coming or not.
Krish NAik: You have to do the installation of the packages, Naga, otherwise Fast API only be accessible to you.
Krish NAik: Looks like I've deleted something.
Krish NAik: Yes, in my case, I have defined the Python version.
Krish NAik: Please, guys, have a check.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… let me start.
Krish NAik: And I will pass some video for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… let me take…
Krish NAik: the attention is all you need. This is a big one, so for sure it will take some time.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the meantime, you can always, look into the logs, exactly what is going on. Okay, so the input is a PDF. Okay, so right now, we are using DocLink, a context-hour chunking strategy that I have applied.
Krish NAik: Converting the document into docklink type, the input format, initializing the pipeline, registered, so this is entirely based on docklink that we have used.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, the total number of chunks which are generated. So right now, what I have done, I'm even performing a catching operation. I'm catching all the chunks, as well as I'm, keeping, the…
Krish NAik: chunks, as well as the embeddings. Both the cache will be created, okay? And successfully absorted 31 vectors to Pinecode.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, for example, if I show you, let's forget about that, let's keep inside our data here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally I have this one. Let's skip catch-it chants.
Krish NAik: Alright, it should load.
Krish NAik: Because it's scaling, it has been saved, but it should save inside this particular folder only.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me just have a check if there is some issue, because I've deleted one folder right now, so I'm just having a check. Save 2, alright, this is the catchier hash that I have.
Krish NAik: And this is the other catcher hash. I'll let everybody please check that the first thing is the upset operation is working or not.
Krish NAik: Everybody.
Krish NAik: It says the API key should be provided while testing the Fast API. Yes, you have to provide the OpenAI API key, otherwise you can't do it.
Krish NAik: Okay? So just be sure you are passing the API key, and it should be detected. If it is not detected in the startup application only, we'll get an error.
Krish NAik: In, this part.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now, see, slash scratching service initialized as temp, alright.
Krish NAik: Because this initialization, I've done it…
Krish NAik: Inside the app, let me check…
Krish NAik: Generally, it should be coming inside this particular folder, but it's telling the slash TMB folder is there.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the server log that I have, let me just delete this one.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, let's try to process, because right now I know,
Krish NAik: The document processed is basically 31 chunks. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: All these chunks will be uploaded to your Pinecone. You can do a verification from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see this is the PDF ID that you have.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that, all the chunks that I have, this, so you can actually look into the text information, what is available.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is a simple context of our chunking operation. So, I know that, yes, for my 31 indexes, it has been uploaded in the first step.
Krish NAik: Everybody please have a check that the data ingestion pipeline is working or not.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, for example, if I upload another PDF for now, okay? So, let me upload another PDF. So, this PDF is done, okay? So, let me choose another file.
Krish NAik: I think in my… Where is this folder?
Krish NAik: Multi-data.
Krish NAik: There you go.
Krish NAik: If I go inside my data, I think at least one…
Krish NAik: PDF somewhere, I'll be keeping it. Upload folder, let me take this file.
Krish NAik: This is a smaller file, actually.
Krish NAik: If you try to hit the same file, so that particular implementation, I will check. Everybody, please check. The Pinecone indexes has been created. Can you show Pinecone indexes has been created? Yes, Pinecone in Texas.
Krish NAik: Here.
Krish NAik: These are my chunks that I have.
Krish NAik: What is the error that you are getting? Santosh, dimension 1536 doesn't match the dimension of the index. Please check your index. During the index creation, I told please select 1536. You have selected 512. Because of that, you are getting the error. Okay? Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, what I will do…
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me check, because I have uploaded another PDF, that climate change PDF, you guys already have that. Okay, from here, again, 37 chunks are created, as you can see. Okay, catch a hit is equal to false. Okay, so let me just pass the same document, and let me see that, whether it's getting there or not.
Krish NAik: Because if the catcher hit is true, then the processing won't be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, the catch rate becomes true, actually, this time. It means that if you try to upload the same document, okay, so simply, like, based on that document ID, it will say that it already is available.
Krish NAik: So, this is one level of optimization that I have done it.
Krish NAik: I have already old index in Pinecone, should I delete and then recreate? Yes. That's the same thing I've done in live class. I had a hyphen documents index, I deleted that, I created a new one.
Krish NAik: You can do that. Please, guys, have a check on these two things.
Krish NAik: Because I know my Major League, this part is done.
Krish NAik: And right now, with respect to…
Krish NAik: Because I have…
Krish NAik: kept it inside that part, so probably with respect to my path, I have to actually check.
Krish NAik: The idea was to check on light.
Krish NAik: It's not necessary if you have the index, the same index can be reused. Otherwise, delete the index, create a new one. Guys, please let me know for how many of you the data ingestion part is working.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, that is the first thing. R working, Abhisheikh working, working, alright? Most of you, okay, it's working.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Alright, working, working, working, a lot of working, I can see. You guys can test out, based on the catch ahead, okay, because right now in my system, it's not getting created. I have to check the issue, because right now it's telling slash 10.
Krish NAik: I feel that inside my user search slash name. If you try to upload the same document, it will say that the catcher hit is true. So please test this particular functionality of catching.
Krish NAik: So actually, the document will load it from the catcher. Because by default, I can see the catch is getting saved in my system, it is in slash temp slash catchy chunks. So I feel that, like, the path definition where I was creating the catcher.
Krish NAik: this… path I need to actually update it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so please check the catching feature. If you try to upload the PDF, the catcher hit is equal to true or not. People for whom it is working.
Krish NAik: Kari and Gupta, please install PDF Miner.
Krish NAik: people, with respect to application part, please check, because PDF Miner, I have kept it in my requirements. I think somewhere, PDF Miner.
Krish NAik: Okay? Please have a check. If you are getting some type of error, you need to fix your, this one.
Krish NAik: what I can say.
Krish NAik: You need to fix your package dependency according to your system.
Krish NAik: The data ingestion part is working.
Krish NAik: Can I move to the next route? Please let me know. Because just to test the application, I'm spending. So, everybody, please let me know, because right now I'm doing the testing.
Krish NAik: And probably, I don't know, like, the next build will come when.
Krish NAik: Alright, it's working, I can see the chunks in Pinecone also. Alright.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's in the temp folder, correct, Utah. It's not getting in the project folder, because of that, that folder is not getting here.
Krish NAik: Because the hash…
Krish NAik: will be created with that only. I have to check that data path in my implementation once.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the desktop 3.
Krish NAik: Alright, can you help me what type of PDF that… upload any PDF, don't ask Mitesh, like, what PDF? The climate change PDF, last time I have shared, you can use that one. I have passed the attention PDF, the research paper, completely.
Krish NAik: Okay, now let's move to the next route, to have a check.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, if you have uploaded some documents, and then if you try to
Krish NAik: list the documents. Here, also, you'll be getting this information, like, based on the documents you have. So, one file name, this is the attention research paper number I know, okay, and then the file name.
Krish NAik: Okay, so simply this part also you can test. Are you getting all the document details?
Krish NAik: Or I think the other route that I have kept, okay, so…
Krish NAik: document count, this also, you can execute it.
Krish NAik: Okay, this time, you can see total uploaded documents is 2, okay? Because, pending queries and other things that I have not, configured right now.
Krish NAik: And the maximum file size limit is 50MB, so pass anything less than 50MB, while the system will reject it.
Krish NAik: When you select Slam, Text, Embit, V2, or any other inference API, I have not used any inference APIs.
Krish NAik: Rahul.
Krish NAik: I've just created a simple index.
Krish NAik: Here, when you go here, back to indexes, when you are creating an index, just select here, text embedding 3 small, okay? And from here, drop down, select 1536. If you have used 512, again, you will get an error.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, if I write anything with respect to climate.
Krish NAik: Yeah, and if I try to look into search right now.
Krish NAik: Is the namespace updated? Because everything will be there in the default, total 68 records, it means the total number of churns.
Krish NAik: currently in the default names field that I have. So, similarly, based… if you, for example, in an organization, if you have multiple departments, you can create multiple namespaces according to those departments, like HR, Finance, and that way, and you can keep their data.
Krish NAik: Okay, directly based on an ID, I don't have.
Krish NAik: Okay, search by vector. Okay, now this is where you can perform multiple search operations, update by metadata. So, these things are available in Pinecone directly in the UI, so you can test that out. Now, I will move to the next one. So, I think the data ingestion part is working.
Krish NAik: This get document part is working, okay? Then comes query the document. Now, this is a document query. It means that, your entire rack pipeline will be invoked, okay? If you parse this.
Krish NAik: So, for example, here,
Krish NAik: What are the impacts of climate change?
Krish NAik: Okay, so I'll write this… let me try to execute.
Krish NAik: Let me see.
Krish NAik: What is the response that we are getting?
Krish NAik: It will be available inside your slash temp slash catch-it chunks, Abhishek.
Krish NAik: Please check the logs, always check the logs.
Krish NAik: Alright, so, this is the question, okay, and based on that, I'm getting the answer.
Krish NAik: Okay, and these are the actual sources which have been used, the relevance courses, 0.63, 0.58, 0.58. Alright, and what are the chunk in Texas? 4th, 7th, and 5th one, majorly that they have picked up.
Krish NAik: Model again GPT-4 Turbo Preview, 3 chunks has been used. Yes, I'm getting the response.
Krish NAik: Okay, please have it checked now in the next step that are you guys getting the response based on the PDF that you have uploaded?
Krish NAik: Please check this route, which is the… Query document route.
Krish NAik: Everybody, please have a check, and then let me know with a yes or no.
Krish NAik: There has to be a query ID.
Krish NAik: Generally, I think it is… Because if you checked, I have not tested the query ID, but I will.
Krish NAik: come to that point, when I will test the spot.
Krish NAik: Okay, please guys tell me, slash query slash documents is working or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, query ID is working, is also working, I checked. I know the query ID is working, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes… this is an intelligent query, it means that this is a unified query. It means that a hybrid routing. It means that based on the query, I have certain keywords in my code database. Based on that, if something is detected, it will do the routing of that query, okay? It can be towards the rack, or towards my text-to-SQL.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for example, here, if I pass, okay? So, by default, you can see auto-approve SQL, this is by default false, try it out. The same question, if I try to pass it. Okay, so from here. Okay, so let me just pass, at least.
Krish NAik: Whereas the unified query is, the server one, okay? Now, here, you have the option auto approve SQL or false. For now, let me keep it the default one. TopK is equal to 3. Let me execute it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it will simply show even, like, where the route is going, because automatically, it should go to the document rack system, okay? So here, you can see the route is
Krish NAik: type document. So here, very specifically, I've kept it. And the route explanation portion, routed to document slash keyword matches, okay, and based on, like, SQL keyword matches also that I have, hybrid keyword matches. So this appears to be a knowledge slash inference query about documentation.
Krish NAik: So that's why, simply, based on that, this particular logic routing has happened. Now, if I ask something with respect to SQL, okay, because this is previous, you guys have already got the response.
Krish NAik: Now, if I ask something from the SQL, okay, so let me just open the notebook of VANA that we have discussed in that class, and let me pick up something from here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… Let me take a query…
Krish NAik: Okay, so for example, how many customers are there in the database?
Krish NAik: So, let me take this one.
Krish NAik: And auto-approve SQL, it means that the SQL execution, it… only the query that will be generated.
Krish NAik: So, execute.
Krish NAik: This time?
Krish NAik: The text-to-SQL agent should be initialized.
Krish NAik: Okay, if the response team is… I think it should be faster somehow. Did I change anything?
Krish NAik: Alright, so based on that, can you see here the question that I have asked, route is SQL, route explanation? Then you have this query ID. Okay, so using this query ID, you can actually do the execution if you want.
Krish NAik: Here, SQL that came, count star as customer from this particular customer, this SQL will retrieve the data. Please review before approving. Status is pending approval, okay? It means that, right now, I'm not given the execution.
Krish NAik: Power. It means that, you should always limit. It means that not everybody should fire your queries, okay? Read and write operations are pretty much costly in any databases.
Krish NAik: So, right here, if you look into the pending queries, you can actually look at… okay, so here, yeah, you can look into this, so this query, that is right now in the pending state. If you want to execute it, you can come here, execute.
Krish NAik: You can pass that query ID, okay, and uproot boolean is equal to true.
Krish NAik: Now we'll be getting the response. Okay, so based on the customer count, that is coming, 200, but I feel it should be 100. Okay, it depends upon the query, customer count from customers.
Krish NAik: Please have a check, because I feel this should be 100. Let me try with another query this time.
Krish NAik: Because previously, the result here that I was getting was 100.
Krish NAik: I hope I'm using the same superbase, but I will test it with another query for now.
Krish NAik: What is the total revenue of all the orders? Let me have a check.
Krish NAik: on this one.
Krish NAik: Yes, if I have inserted the data multiple times.
Krish NAik: I don't think I have executed the same script two times. If that comes, then this also should be up and working.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine, let me test it with another query, okay? And this time, the unified query, what I will do…
Krish NAik: Query, unified query, let me make it true, auto-approve.
Krish NAik: They handled it to me. Okay, what is the total revenue from all the orders that we see?
Krish NAik: The root hybrid that it has picked up.
Krish NAik: SQL that is getting generated, some total distributor revenue, this is the main result, alright. This is a SQL component result. Now, I do have a hybrid one, where it means that it can try to look from both the output.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the other output which is not relevant to us. So, simply, you can see I don't have enough information. So, based on that, you can actually reject the query. So, that particular approach also, it's there.
Krish NAik: Alright, now… because this is pretty much keyword-based implementation, so it's not very much robust, I can add more keywords to make it better.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's based on keywords, simply. Like, if you really look into the implementation, okay, within your, let me just go into this one.
Krish NAik: Where is your app? Inside app, you will be having this service. So if you look into this router service, can you see a lot of SQL keywords that I have kept?
Krish NAik: So, based on this particular keyword, only trying to detect, and based on the document keywords.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… And some hybrid keywords are also there.
Krish NAik: Well, right now, this route is working, okay? And last time, the pending SQL query was there. If I try to list, it should be blank this time, because all the queries that I have executed. So I can see that the core functionality is working. So everybody, please do have a check on the core functionality. And if I look into the catch stats, okay, try it out, directly I can look into.
Krish NAik: Okay, total two documents are there, which has been captured.
Krish NAik: Okay, and these are the hash IDs of those catcher which has been created. So, the catcher contains two documents, so all the document catching also that I am doing.
Krish NAik: I will come to codebase, first of all, check the functionality, then I will come to the codebase. At least, the thing that I'm building, it should be up and working in your system.
Krish NAik: Go to base, I will come. Don't worry.
Krish NAik: But first of all, check all the functionalities, because majorly, I think all the routes have been checked from my side. So if you want to clear the cache, so that particular option also, I've kept it, but don't use it for now. It's better to have a…
Krish NAik: Catch it. Right now, I'm not using any external databases directly, I'm saving it.
Krish NAik: So, everybody, please do the testing of all the routes, and then let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, so everybody, please have a check with respect to the routes. If your routes are working, then it's good. Then we can start ahead with the implementation part.
Krish NAik: Now, Maya, can you share, the PDF? Just get the attention is all you need. Any paper, you can do it, Satish. It's not that my paper, only you need it.
Krish NAik: Okay, I have uploaded the climate change PDF, you guys have already had that in the last class of advanced rat tutorials I have shared, I have uploaded that.
Krish NAik: So typically, we have a rag where we need to upload the doc embeddc here, how one adds value slash adds a new purpose.
Krish NAik: Nope.
Krish NAik: my, text-to-SQL service is totally different. There is the separate tables, and we have a rag where we upload the doc. So, similarly, here we are uploading the doc. When you are uploading the doc, that becomes a RAG.
Krish NAik: Both the things are… one, you have RAG, one you have your Texas SQL agent. Now you have to just perform that routing.
Krish NAik: I meant in RAG how text-to-SQL adds value. If you… see, generally, if you have lesser tables, you can work with Llama or with Landshain. I feel it's good. But really, when it's more and more very big tables, more than 1,000 tables, then you can actually
Krish NAik: Feel that it will be going down.
Krish NAik: At least, have a check with, let's…
Krish NAik: packed, because, again, if I try to generate a SQL,
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the SQL generation. Only the SQL will be generated. I think this route I have not tested. Let me test this route also. I think something from…
Krish NAik: Our service of our…
Krish NAik: This is my data gadget channels right now, I will save inside this one.
Krish NAik: So, this is the SQL generation. Okay.
Krish NAik: So, your text to SQL, no querying of the file, let me see.
Krish NAik: Alright, select name, email from customers where countries equal to USA.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… query ID, again.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this, if I try to copy it… And if I list…
Krish NAik: Okay, execute. One query is pending. Execute. Let me update this one.
Krish NAik: Cool.
Krish NAik: Alright, okay, this information is coming, correct name with the email. Fine.
Krish NAik: Alright, immediately, so all the routes I have tested, so everybody, please let me know that
Krish NAik: The testing of the router is done, then we will start building it from scratch entirely.
Krish NAik: Because I have done all the testing, so in your case, also, everything should be up and working. Viraj is asking, can you please discuss high-level overview discussing in README?
Krish NAik: Yes, this is a catching operation where I'm generating that SHA256 hash, just to check the deduplication of chums or the embeddings.
Krish NAik: Varage.
Krish NAik: Okay, ERM64 is much cheaper as compared to x86 or 64.
Krish NAik: So, I will be using AWS Lambda. So, in Lambda, with ARM64, architectures are much more cheaper. That's why Virajaib uses it.
Krish NAik: So, for example, the cost reduction is basically, if you try to upload the same document, it will say the catch is it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that was the main purpose, so that the same document, multiple times, you don't need to re-upload it, it will be picked up from the catch.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… let me know for how many of you all the routes are working perfectly fine.
Krish NAik: Angosh, fine. Subhash, alright.
Krish NAik: What about others? Asma Sultana working, alright? Working, working, everybody plays right, working, working, because here, many folks are there. And for how many of you, few are working, and few are not working. For how many of you, nothing is working.
Krish NAik: There can be 3 conditions. All working, few working, 0 working.
Krish NAik: Alright, everything is working, all working, few working, alright. Not working because of config issues, alright.
Krish NAik: Query ID generated, but executed the section, it put query ID, did not shoot for home, stuck at uploading the document due to some dependency issue, but solving it now. Alright, take your time, try to solve it. Okay? People for whom it's working, great. Okay, so you can…
Krish NAik: Test and, like, few other things that you can.
Krish NAik: Check it out, but let's wait for 5 minutes, and then I will look into it.
Krish NAik: Alright, getting the response with respect to an agent, it can be confusing, so you can simply wait, I think, let's stop 3…
Krish NAik: First of all, check the responses are coming, at least some response. It means that the functionality is working. Later on, we will look into whether it's correct or not.
Krish NAik: So take 5 minutes.
Krish NAik: Everybody, because really, these things, you need to resolve it by yourself.
Krish NAik: Use ChatGBT, use anything but spend time.
Krish NAik: In the meantime, a few people were asking with respect to text-to-SQL benchmarking, okay, as I told you about Spyder, I'm sharing one link if people are interested. Okay, you can actually look into some metrics for NL SQL type of task.
Krish NAik: Because I think then, next week, I will start the scratch implementation, because once you have done the testing today of the core app, probably through functionality, I might change it this weekend.
Krish NAik: Okay, because a little bit of logging and other things with respect to opaque integrations that are remaining from my site, that I will complete it. Okay, and that catch issue also I will look into.
Krish NAik: So, people, please take your time and try to resolve, because… Before taking the doubts.
Krish NAik: I think I can do that. Subhash, can you explain about the catchy in detail about explaining the project so that I can implement it in real time? In real time, you need a proper database. Right now, I'm not using any databases, Subhash, but you can use Redis or something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can look into the catching service, because when I'll be showing you the implementation, okay, this is the main script that you can look into.
Krish NAik: services. Here, you will be having your caching service.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can look into this particular implementation with respect to catch.
Krish NAik: Later on, you can upgrade it and use the Redis server.
Krish NAik: So here, actually, I'm generating the SHA256, if you really look into SHA256. This one.
Krish NAik: Because, I need to check the catch-up path definition, because I feel that this catch-up path
Krish NAik: Okay, based on the document ID, this I need to update it.
Krish NAik: Because I'm saving the embedding cache, okay, the metadata also, and the chunks. So this one, it's getting saved in a different folder. So I need to update it with the right folder path.
Krish NAik: Yes, Satish, it will take time, it's a big paper.
Krish NAik: Others, please check for whom it's not working.
Krish NAik: Okay, for any type of SQL query, this folder will be getting created, deleted.
Krish NAik: It's actually not required.
Krish NAik: These are for your VANA SQL.
Krish NAik: queries.
Krish NAik: Almost renewable generated SAP? Okay, really like it in.
Krish NAik: Closed Technology SAP.
Krish NAik: It's not working to do… link my other script and the main script. Really, Amar, I have no idea, like, what is the reason it can be. Without the implementation, it's very hard to see.
Krish NAik: the query ID will be generated, sorry.
Krish NAik: If… It will be generated.
Krish NAik: Whenever you, like, generate, then also it will be coming.
Krish NAik: Okay, so then, once you have that, you can list the number of queries, and then you can do the execution.
Krish NAik: Try to use smaller PDFs, otherwise the embedding will take time.
Krish NAik: Yes, you can create a separate file only. A simple PY file, Mitesh.
Krish NAik: Markdown and other file are not required. Simple. You can keep it in Markdown also, because generally Markdown formats are suggestible. Don't keep it in CSV format. Keep it in Markdown or a PY file as a variable. As simple as that. Later on, get that.
Krish NAik: Breed.
Krish NAik: Right now, OPIC is not required. If you guys want to create, create the OPIC API key, okay, a few people are telling, just, go to comment, okay? So, like, this is my…
Krish NAik: 1.
Krish NAik: So, you can simply sign up and commit and get your API key. Okay, so just do a Google sign-in.
Krish NAik: And directly from the settings window, you will get it. So, comment…
Krish NAik: Okay, if you want, just click on here, you will get the API key, copy-paste it in your EMV file. It takes 2 minutes to create the API key, not more than that.
Krish NAik: You should get the response with the query ID, as others have also confirmed. Please have a check.
Krish NAik: Test all the routes. That is the basic requirement for now.
Krish NAik: Because in the next class, when I'll be starting from the scratch.
Krish NAik: the same routes I'll be building, so at least the main implementation that I have done, it should be up and working in your system.
Krish NAik: Sharav's telling how to check the routes.
Krish NAik: Open, like, open the Swaggery wipe, and check the routes.
Krish NAik: These are routes only that I am showing you. Okay, we have to check these routes.
Krish NAik: does not work right. It works, no? So, for example, like, generate the SQL last time. For example, when I executed this, okay, so before execution, I'm showing you list pending queries. Right now, if I do the execution, you will see that zero pending queries. But once I, do the generation of this one.
Krish NAik: So, like, okay.
Krish NAik: And then you will see, it will be available inside the list of pending queries. Now, this zero will be updated. Can you see here the query ID that came?
Krish NAik: Okay, now this query ID, you can take it, and you can execute it in
Krish NAik: the SQL, slash execute SQL in this route.
Krish NAik: I have tested all the routes, and all the routes are working. Please have it checked from your side that all the routes are working or not.
Krish NAik: Are the query ID used for catching? Right now, I'm not doing that. I've not applied catching for our text-to-SQL. If you want, you can do a catching of the query ID also.
Krish NAik: Right now, for catching, I'm just doing the document-level catching implementation that I have done.
Krish NAik: Because to make it much more robust, I will suggest use Redis. That's the thing.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, guys, in the chat, how many of you were able to resolve.
Krish NAik: Because if this part should be up and working in your system, at least all the routes that I have showed you.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, let me know, let me know, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, because if I start taking doubts, I feel, then there would be nothing to discuss, that's why.
Krish NAik: I don't get… I don't have enough 10 minutes to answer the question, please upload the relevant document first for every query I have asked.
Krish NAik: Imran, like, really, I'm not sure, like, I don't have enough information. This is fine, this is in the, I know the prompt zone is…
Krish NAik: Yeah, relevant for every query. Just check with respect to your…
Krish NAik: Chunks and other things based on the query that you are passing.
Krish NAik: Working all routes, the document is uploaded.
Krish NAik: If the document is uploaded, then for sure it should throw you the response.
Krish NAik: Because that becomes…
Krish NAik: Because I don't have… I have not created a retrieval route here, just to show you the…
Krish NAik: iterated one, because last time I have done that particular implementation, so the same thing that can be kept here.
Krish NAik: Pending queries are also working, alright. For major of you, it's working, I can see. Few people are stuck.
Krish NAik: So, if you are stuck, I need to look into that.
Krish NAik: It's 11.35… Alright.
Krish NAik: I will look into the routes. In the meantime.
Krish NAik: everybody create a blank folder for our Scratch implementation for next week that we'll be doing.
Krish NAik: Okay? People, just, because at least create a blank folder, keep the requirements file, which are common things to do a setup for a project, you can do a copy-paste and create a blank folder. Okay. REST implementation, I'll be doing it from scratch.
Krish NAik: And let me look into, now, the problems you were facing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so people who want to drop, you guys can drop, because really I need to look into this issue, then really I can start the implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, okay, so in the meantime, let me start with the…
Krish NAik: Everybody please create a blank folder, this is a request, so even I'll be creating a new folder for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, so my… okay, I will give a name.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… touch to SQL…
Krish NAik: Alright, so let's do the common setup.
Krish NAik: Open folder, a new window.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, move the files which are required. So, what are the major files? Don't move, just keep, at least move your requirement.txt, okay? Because you need to do the setup, move your .env.env.example. These files are required. Please move there.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this entire app folder, we will be doing the implementation from scratch, so you can create the folder structure by creating the blank files.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that particular operation, you can do it by yourself.
Krish NAik: Here, you will be getting your logs.
Krish NAik: For logs, there is a dedicated folder, Sara Parma.
Krish NAik: Hold it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, everybody, please create a blank folder, so start creating that, as I have. Okay, so your requirement.txt, you can directly do a copy-paste of these files.
Krish NAik: For example, let me just…
Krish NAik: I think it will be better if you do a copy-paste, because it's the same one, 3 billion finder. So what are the files that you need, actually? Okay, so, for example, you will be requiring your requirement.txt, where is your requirementRRRR
Krish NAik: Yes, your requirement.txt, this file you need, and create the…
Krish NAik: this folder structure. This folder structure is important. It means that you create the blank folders for now. So later on, at least for whom everything is working, later on, you don't need to spend time by creating the folder structure. So today, at least create everything with respect to this app folder.
Krish NAik: Create all the blank files. Config.py, login config, main.py. Okay, everybody please do create. And finally, the services.
Krish NAik: Okay, so all the services that you have, create the plan files for today.
Krish NAik: See, you can create a script also if somebody is a bit smart. Okay, simply based on the folder structure, you can ask any LLM to create a script.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that script, you can actually create that entire folder structure. If you don't want to do it manually, even I don't love, generally, I create a template. So you can create a file, template.py, execute that file, and get the entire folder structure. Okay? So in that way, also, you can do it.
Krish NAik: Alright, project.tml is fine, I will add it in the next one only. It's not… because right now, generally, I prefer working with PyProject.tml file when I have packages much more. This time, I don't have a lot of package-based implementation, so I have not kept the PyProject 2ML workflow.
Krish NAik: But… that's fine. So, guys, for whom it's working, you can do that setup. Now, let me look into the doubts. So, people who want to drop, you guys can drop. Okay, next week, I will start the scratch implementation.
Krish NAik: Alright, let me look into the doubts for people who are having the issue, because really, with respect to the issues, I cannot… Imran, okay, your one, Satish.
Krish NAik: Okay, then Rajat, Rahul, Unam, okay, you guys, one by one. People who want to share their screen, they want to.
Satish Tiwari: Hi, buddy.
Krish NAik: Spyder is a benchmark method, there is no demo in that. It's a benchmark-based dataset which has been used.
Rahul Parihar: So, Paul, for being here, things are working, I just wanted to share the screen,
Rahul Parihar: I'm getting.
Krish NAik: Tell me that if something is not working, then only tell me. If things are working, then I'll tell right now.
Rahul Parihar: No, so the document, the query that you're trying to, send, like, how…
Rahul Parihar: which customers are from US, you know, the CURI connection to…
Rahul Parihar: to the database, the super… super base, you know? That query is not resulting any result.
Rahul Parihar: When I'm uploading a document, documents parsing is working fine.
Rahul Parihar: So, what could be the reason? Like…
Krish NAik: Really, like, I'm even not sure, because if in my case it's working the same codebase for you also, but as an internal working of agent, it's not deterministic when multiple agents' call happens, so the response can be different.
Krish NAik: So, but check the API should be working, that's the major… if the API is working, later on, we can look into that. Right now, I'll be focused on whether the API or the route is working or not.
Krish NAik: So, is it connect the application, this application, is it connected to the super database and the data that we have created? Correct. It is connected with the database.
Rahul Parihar: It is connected, right? So, which query should be able to generate the SQL generate query, execute, and pending.
Krish NAik: generate query will only generate the SQL. Execute will do the SQL execution. It means that the read operation, okay, that particular on top of your supervis that it will be doing, only two things are there.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, so that functionality is not working. We can look it into later, right?
Krish NAik: Alright, that part… just check the API should be up and working, that's my main priority. If the API is not working, nothing will work that way.
Rahul Parihar: Got it. Okay.
Krish NAik: Thanks. All right.
Krish NAik: Next, with respect to APIs not working, first of all, tell me.
Imran A: Hi, sir.
Krish NAik: Can you hear this?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, I can hear.
Imran A: So, in my case, everything is working fine, but when I run… when I ask for a particular question from the document, then it always gives me that output.
Krish NAik: Tell me the API, it means that the API is working.
Krish NAik: API is working, then don't… I want to look into issues, first of all, where API is not working.
Krish NAik: Slash, as well.
Krish NAik: Imran, your API is working.
Imran A: Okay.
Krish NAik: The response is different. I'm looking into the issues where the API is only not working, that is the first priority. Then I will look into that one. People whose API is not working, please raise your hands in the first case. It means that I have to look into the implementation part. At least if the API is working, you'll be getting some response.
Krish NAik: But in the first case, only if everything fails, then nothing that…
Krish NAik: I could do. So first, let's check that issue, because this is a bigger application, so for sure there will be…
Krish NAik: There's some sort of issues. Yes, Poona.
Imran A: Focus.
Satish Tiwari: Alright, buddy.
Poonam Nanda: Can I share my screen? For me, the settings itself is not getting loaded, I've tried multiple things, but I'm not able to start that.
Krish NAik: I will add you to panelist, you can share your screen. Okay? Now, next…
Satish Tiwari: Hello?
Krish NAik: Yes, Atish?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Satish Tiwari: Oh, actually, my cell, 2 cell is not working, that, I have seen you.
Krish NAik: Alright, we told that the data statistics fine. If it is not working, the other cells are working, no.
Satish Tiwari: Yes, other sensors are working, okay.
Krish NAik: That is fine.
Satish Tiwari: Even API is also working.
Krish NAik: And really, see, when I'm talking about a lot of things with respect to agents are non-deterministic. So, really, nobody knew that this is a static rule. If you are doing this, you are getting that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, even with respect to any agentic-based framework, it's a common thing.
Satish Tiwari: Okay, and also.
Krish NAik: what you talk about?
Satish Tiwari: Output is also getting changed, so that is not, that is a thing's okay, correct?
Krish NAik: Yes. So, tell me about the API. API is working on…
Satish Tiwari: API is working, APA is working.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine.
Krish NAik: People for whom the API is not working, please let me know first. I will be looking into that.
Krish NAik: Others, samplat.
Krish NAik: Okay, Naga, then you have, Rajat, everybody. People, first of all, tell me the API is working or not. If API is not working, nothing that we can do in the next step. Parentic issue, config updated, alright, fine.
Krish NAik: The Rajat, Sambat, right?
Rajat Khanna: So everything is working for me, Paul, just for the same question I had, SQL query one.
Krish NAik: leave that part. SQL query, it means that working, but again, when I'm working with agents, it's not deterministic, so that thing can change.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, yeah, so it is working for me.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Here, huh.
Krish NAik: Okay, somebody is…
samapth reddy vummanthala: When I'm running this Yubicon from the app, folder, it is saying, socket is not connected, some error is coming.
Krish NAik: Alright, now you can share. The socket issue happens sometimes.
Krish NAik: This is with respect to your SQL server?
Poonam Nanda: visible?
Krish NAik: Yes, Poonam, you can start sharing, you are in the panelist.
Krish NAik: I have already shared.
Krish NAik: No, I cannot see your screen.
Poonam Nanda: Sorry, sir.
Poonam Nanda: Is it visible now?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: You're taking time to load, and that's the thing.
Krish NAik: Okay, I think Poonam's screen… okay, now I can see. All right.
Poonam Nanda: So, we have added all the configs in the config.py as well, and env as well.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes. People who want to drop, they can drop. Nothing I'll be discussing, I'll be just looking into the issues.
Krish NAik: Okay, people who want to drop, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Just before next class, just be sure you have that template ready with blank files. That is the basic requirement for next class, otherwise you have to manually create it. If somebody can do that, you can raise a PR in my repo also, I will accept your PR.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes. So, here, Poonam, you were telling… What is not working?
Poonam Nanda: The application itself is not getting started, so I guess the settings… in the settings itself, I'm facing issue, but till the last line of the settings, it is getting executed. You'll see all the print statements I'm getting. But if you'll see in the log, it says…
Krish NAik: This is UVCon issue settings, line number 61.
Krish NAik: This is a main call through the settings.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, similar issue for me as well, Paul.
Poonam Nanda: Inside settings, it is… I have given the pin statements, and it is executing till the end.
Krish NAik: Giving print statement is not exactly which property is creating that issue. We have to look into that one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Poonam Nanda: I tried printing at least few of the RMs I tried, like, OpenAPI Key, and then all these. I tried printing them as well.
Krish NAik: Alright, this API you have passed.
Krish NAik: Because if it fails, this is the first check to start the application.
Krish NAik: One thing you can do, just pass the rest of the API keys also, your OP KPI key and others, everything pass it, because your error also…
Poonam Nanda: Paiki, I commented.
Krish NAik: Opic API key, pass it. Okay, just pass everything.
Poonam Nanda: It is also saying something… actually, I was checking with the ChatGPT, and it was saying that user… it is looking for the user password and all those things, but we are giving the entire URL, so you should not look for the user password and all these things, right? The DB.
Krish NAik: Yes, correct.
Krish NAik: Shall I add those as well? Because my DB URL…
Krish NAik: Because directly in your config file, when you have passed it.
Krish NAik: Because my DB URL, I have not passed it only here.
Krish NAik: It's getting picked up from .dv. I don't know where you got that, because in my case, I've just kept it none.
Satish Tiwari: I haven't done the override. I was getting the same issue. Can you go to .env? Can you go to .env, right?
Poonam Nanda: Yeah, just a second, I feel like I've been…
Satish Tiwari: Have you written any hardcore host? Yes, comment it, this one. Comment it all.
Krish NAik: Okay, this…
Poonam Nanda: Oh, it's sick.
Krish NAik: Commentator, all for me.
Satish Tiwari: One time.
Satish Tiwari: Another one.
Krish NAik: In class, I told to do the comment.
Satish Tiwari: Then you have to find that number.
Satish Tiwari: In country final, you have to give none.
Satish Tiwari: Whatever you have passed that hard code, no?
Satish Tiwari: Otherwise, do one thing, you replace the same config file, from,
Poonam Nanda: So, in the config where,
Poonam Nanda: I have to give none. What exactly I have to give none?
Krish NAik: DB URL, DB URL.
Poonam Nanda: Actually, DB URL, I don't need to give there, okay? Everything was now, actually, I added only, sorry, then I'll do Ctrl-Z in that case.
Satish Tiwari: Yeah, it was like…
Poonam Nanda: is…
Satish Tiwari: How can I repeat.
Poonam Nanda: Cool, cool, cool. It was not working, so I, actually tried giving them.
Satish Tiwari: Don't take it anymore.
Krish NAik: Alright, so watch file detected changes in app config. The app is getting reloaded, let's wait.
Krish NAik: Because the main environment variables, you'll be keeping it in .bnb.
Krish NAik: From there, we will do the check.
Krish NAik: Okay. In settings files, you don't need to hardcode, because this setting file, we share with you guys.
Krish NAik: If I expose my API key, it's a bad thing, even for open API key also.
Krish NAik: You have hard-coded it.
Krish NAik: So I don't keep those things, because later on, I'll be loading them through .en. That is the main purpose.
Krish NAik: Alright, Naga, yes, Naga, your issue?
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, highball somebody, yeah? So… Should I share my screen, so…
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, start sharing. If you're in Parallels, don't ask, directly start sharing.
Krish NAik: Yes, Naga, your issue?
Naga: Yeah, I want to share my screen. I'm getting a similar…
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, let me see.
Krish NAik: Local host 8000 slash docs, so here you are getting somewhere a new module named app.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Okay.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Seeing.
Krish NAik: First of all, see, your project structure, multidata project slash main, then insider, again, multi-data project, because of this structured thing, you are getting that.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Oh, is it?
Krish NAik: Yes, because of the project structure, the way that I have the structure, a single folder, that multi-data, inside that you should have all the files, not a folder within a folder, then it becomes a problem for the compiler to understand.
Naga: Yeah, I'm getting this, and I'm loading.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So I should redo all the things, right?
Krish NAik: It's not redo, that folder structure you have to change, you have to keep everything inside that project data.
Krish NAik: Multidata rack project that you have.
Krish NAik: So, I solved this, because you guys are not taking a clone, it looks like you have taken a zip.
Krish NAik: Because of that zip, it creates a problem.
samapth reddy vummanthala: If you have taken a clone of my repo, then this problem won't arise, actually.
Krish NAik: Okay, so only that, structure. So, I'm telling I solved this, I can help, okay?
Krish NAik: Just to take a closer and raise your hand.
Naga: I can… So, I'm getting this error.
Krish NAik: wait, wait, Naga, I'm looking into now Sampas issue, then I will raise, okay? Suham, yes.
Krish NAik: swamped it.
E2317: Like, can you go to your, settings.py or config.py?
samapth reddy vummanthala: Oh, mate.
E2317: configure P.
samapth reddy vummanthala: app for learning.
E2317: It will ha- it will be under app.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, it's a 11.
E2317: Go to config.py.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, same thing called Fever.
E2317: One minute, just scroll down.
E2317: So, all of these variables should be by default present, and no other extra variables should be present in .env.
E2317: So I had this issue where I had kept some extra variable in .env, and as a result, it gave me that error.
samapth reddy vummanthala: This problem I face, because here I have added extra, because I hard-coded directly.
E2317: No, no.
samapth reddy vummanthala: You can't.
E2317: Did you mention extra variables?
E2317: So if you go to .env, right?
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah. Go to dotty.
E2317: Can we fight?
samapth reddy vummanthala: This is RTL, so here I have added extra.
E2317: I'm not able to use .envy.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Nope.
Krish NAik: This is .env, it looks like, but why you have updated so many things? No, the thing is, it needs to be used.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Paul, that the problem is that if I use the directly database URL, it is, failing. So…
samapth reddy vummanthala: The connection, so what I did, so I have manually, I did all the things. Now…
samapth reddy vummanthala: when you run this app configuration, now I'm able to connect successfully, because I've now.
Krish NAik: skate.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So, it is… database URL is a problem, so it's not, parsing is always failing.
Naga: Correct, yeah, that's a big problem, actually, Anthony.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So, that's the reason, I have made, manually, like, created a database URL. So, this was working fine. So, all the connections, everything is working fine.
Krish NAik: Manually, then, you have created, okay, the same logic that data you.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So, same logic I have uploaded here, config.py, so…
E2317: Can you go to the .env?
samapth reddy vummanthala: dot ENV in the app folder, right? So, I'm in.
E2317: Yes, yes, no, no.en would be the one that is there in your first… Next.
E2317: The first one, the leftmost one.
samapth reddy vummanthala: These are notebooks?
samapth reddy vummanthala: No, no.envy is there, right? Yeah.
E2317: Can we… Vana? No, you are open… you have opened config.t. Why?
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, yeah.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Pandolous.
E2317: Just click on .env file.
Satish Tiwari: Naga, pasted, pasted, not the enemy.
E2317: First step, yes.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, dishonored, right?
E2317: No, no, no, this is not… Go to .env file.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Most tab.
Krish NAik: Do you have to take care of.
samapth reddy vummanthala: This is the first time on it, right? Multidata Project Man under the folder E&E.
Krish NAik: No, I'm not able to… is anyone able to see .env file? I'm already… Oh, yes, yes, yes, this is the .env file you're sharing, I can see.
Naga: Yeah, that is a Yin refer, yeah.
Krish NAik: I think now, anybody else is sharing the screen, they can.
Naga: Yeah, yeah, I'm there, I'm there, can I?
Krish NAik: Look into sample screen very specifically, then.
Krish NAik: You're positive.
Krish NAik: So, just stop sharing only, like, right now, we are looking into sample screen.
E2317: env, right, that, yes. If you scroll down…
Krish NAik: youth.
E2317: Huh, so, so this is .en we have. Go there, correct?
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah.
E2317: So, what I had done is, at the end, like, I have copied all the settings from the previous yesterday's project, and I have hard-coded all this in the line number 30 to 42, right? So this is not referenced in your settings… in your config PY, so it was throwing an error.
E2317: So, what I did was, as Sir mentioned, I just mentioned the database URL here, and mentioned the database URL none there. So by default, the config dictionary picks it from here.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, that's funny.
E2317: fix that issue. If you just… so database URL, yes, you can uncomment this, you can comment out this, if you see, yes, comment out also database URL.
samapth reddy vummanthala: enough, though.
E2317: No, no, you keep, sorry, you keep this database URL? Yes.
E2317: Yes, you can keep… no, comment the line number 34.
samapth reddy vummanthala: It'll go okay.
E2317: 34.
E2317: Huh, comment line number 34?
E2317: And go to env.py.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Ian, yeah.
E2317: And so, uncomment the line number 25.
samapth reddy vummanthala: 25… this is… I know, you know, it's not there.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So, these are 43s…
E2317: So, actually, you can hardcode all the variable there. Don't keep any of the Postgres host anything. Just hardcode the exact variable there. Database URL, what you have mentioned in line number 25.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yes, sir. Uncomment? Yes, uncomment?
samapth reddy vummanthala: But it is…
Krish NAik: For you, it's line number 43 only, just update that Postgres, those variables update it. Postgres user directly keeps the user.
E2317: Yes, and…
Krish NAik: Don't use…
E2317: Everything from 38 to 42.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Uncomment, comment, right?
E2317: Comment out?
E2317: Comment, 38 to 42.
E2317: Yes, sorry. Okay, no, not a problem. And… Huh.
E2317: And then, comment line number 43 also.
samapth reddy vummanthala: 43 also.
E2317: Yes, and uncomment line number 25.
samapth reddy vummanthala: 25. Yes.
E2317: So how it works is, first your config.py, if it is none, it will pick it from env file.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Okay.
E2317: Oh, you can… now, if you run uvicon. Just check whether it's working or not.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, I had to change this, connection.
E2317: Just change that.
Krish NAik: According to your variables, do that.
E2317: Actually, so I missed some of your, like, that API URL in the FastAPI browser. I'll probably go after the class. I was fixing this issue during the class.
samapth reddy vummanthala: This is this one, right? So, I enabled this one, so most probably…
E2317: But bracket will not be there, I'm guessing.
Krish NAik: This one? Yes. Bracket won't be there.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Okay.
Krish NAik: Directly, it has to be the password.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So, shall I run now?
E2317: just check if all of this URL is correct.
samapth reddy vummanthala: database URL this year is there, and config.py, I have uncommented this one. So this… should I uncomment this one also? Comment also, something?
E2317: Yes, yes, configure, just comment out.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Better, I will do that. So, only one database URL there.
E2317: Alright, great.
Krish NAik: do a Ctrl-S, automatically it will start. If any changes are there, it will suggest.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay, now the folder structure. No module named that? Because of the folder structure, this error comes.
E2317: Unto app.main colon app.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, he has passed that same statement, but look into his… there is a folder within a folder, because of that, it is not getting detected.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Okay, okay.
E2317: Within a folder… okay.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Okay, I got, I got the one.
Krish NAik: Yeah, that project may know.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah.
Krish NAik: because of that folder.
samapth reddy vummanthala: So, there are too many multiple folders out.
Krish NAik: Yes, because of that nested structure. Now, Nala…
samapth reddy vummanthala: Can you show me…
Krish NAik: your issue.
Naga: Just.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, thank you, thank you, I'll… I'll check in.
Naga: Fuck no.
Krish NAik: Sanjay is there, Sanjay Sabor? Yes, Sanjay?
Sanjay Sagore: Yes, Paul, thanks.
Sanjay Sagore: I think I'm getting issue while uploading that one. So, I thought that it is the, basically.
Sanjay Sagore: Something is blocking. Mike, let me show you.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will add you to panelist. Yes, Naga, your issue?
Naga: Ubicorn, this went out of account, so… Huicong…
Naga: Finance, finance, real.
Naga: Yeah, I'm getting the similar, like, extra forbidden, so…
Krish NAik: Excellent.
Naga: inputs, you have passed it in your config.yml file that you might have not passed in .env. Check. In ENV.
Krish NAik: See, user app, these things, I have not kept it, okay? I told you, comment that out.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, simply in your…
Krish NAik: Because you have kept… this is your .env file, no? Yes, comment that, comment, comment, comment. Directly use that db URL thing, that the same thing that you need to pass.
Naga: Dvorl, I have two DVRLs.
Krish NAik: Because you can't pass extra, because there is a check. Because of that, it's telling added 1.
Naga: So are we DVRAN like this, okay? Like, 54, 32, or should I use the 65…
Krish NAik: If you have an IPv4 from your ISP, use the session puller.
Krish NAik: It is suggested, if you are working with IPv4, then that.
Naga: slot I have. IPv4 issue is there for me, so I'm commenting that one. Anything else? Anything else?
Krish NAik: REST, user, password, host, comment, all those things, you don't need.
Naga: Awesome. Okay.
Naga: Yes, everything is commented now.
Krish NAik: do a Ctrl-S, automatically the… And check your config file once.
Krish NAik: config.py, is there any extra entries or not?
Krish NAik: Have you done any changes here?
Naga: Nothing, I'm not touching this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine. Then, just do a slash.
Krish NAik: Do a control list, and then try to restart the app once more.
Krish NAik: Ctrl-C, C, C, Ctrl-C, the app will close from the terminal. Go to Terminal, do a Ctrl-C, app arrow key, hit enter.
Krish NAik: Let Lena.
Krish NAik: If there is a single extra entry, it will throw you the error.
Krish NAik: That's funny.
Naga: Hmm.
Naga: Looks like it's going to go through and off.
Naga: TV.
Naga: And that notebook also was giving an error in the middle, something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this connection screen, have you checked it by executing that file con… Test connection.
Naga: Yeah, definitely.
Krish NAik: Because, see, right now, you can see the initialization has taken place.
Naga: But, like.
Krish NAik: age.
Naga: Facing the booking.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, API, OpenAI API key, OPEC API key, have you configured yet?
Naga: No, not yet.
Krish NAik: Okay, then leave it, then fine, if it has paid, not a worry. You can open now docs. Localhost slash docs, localhost 8000 docs, you can open that.
Naga: Yeah, from Obinal.
Naga: Yeah, in the coming next.
Krish NAik: Yes, it's fine then. If it is coming like this, the rest is.
Naga: Oh, God.
Krish NAik: testing.
Naga: Per Docker, or…
Krish NAik: Your app is working, now you do the testing with respect to the app, okay?
Naga: Okay, bro.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, next, who want to share their screen?
Sanjay Sagore: Nope.
Krish NAik: Sanjay? Savoda?
Sanjay Sagore: Okay.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, I'm setting up.
Sanjay Sagore: So, here it is, Paul.
Sanjay Sagore: We're actually calling that upload API now.
Krish NAik: Upload API, alright? When you are uploading, it's saying that. Connection.py… Yes, all the time.
Sanjay Sagore: I think it's blocking this, certificate will have been…
Krish NAik: this is an SSL verification, very generally this happens.
Krish NAik: Due to bad internet connection.
Krish NAik: We're doing the…
Sanjay Sagore: This is my company laptop, so might they have blocked, or some, some,
Sanjay Sagore: Settings, security setting is there. I feel like that.
Sanjay Sagore: But I just want to know which particular API it is failing, or…
Krish NAik: See, C, see, see, see, see, go below. When it's trying to do the… see, right here, when you look into the logs, okay? Catch a miss for the document, okay, CSGAN, PDF, preparing the chunking. This is connection to your fine cone.
Sanjay Sagore: Fine, I'm okay.
Krish NAik: Pinkoon connection.
Krish NAik: If you are confident that you are using… then use a browser-based ID, no? Generally, for your office laptop, I suggest you can use a browser-based ID.
Sanjay Sagore: No.
Krish NAik: Lightning or something browser-based ID, where you can do all the executions, there are no restrictions.
Krish NAik: Previously, I have shown you. Alright, Soham, I saw that.
Sanjay Sagore: In browser, it will, will block only some, some URL.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, no. Where I'm telling you, it's web-based browser.
Krish NAik: It's nothing related to… Is Mita, nothing from your local that you were doing.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, means web-based, the development… Yes, like AWS, SageMaker, okay, if you do this, those are hosted, so you can try this, because it looks like it's rejecting the Pinecone connection, that's it.
Sanjay Sagore: Yes, right, like, okay, I have the remote server I have, so I will try with that.
Krish NAik: Oh, check out.
Naga: Never coming for me, can I share my screen, please?
Krish NAik: Yes, everyone panel is start sharing.
Sanjay Sagore: Okay, okay, Paul, thanks, thanks. I'll try again.
Naga: Oh, Paul, when I run the… this notebook, right, it's, giving…
Naga: Could not translate the host name.
Naga: Will the service at all.
Krish NAik: Have you updated the notebook? Inside the notebook, you had that VNV file?
Naga: ENV file is this common, right? This comma.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, the VNV file inside the notebooks folder. You have to… I told you, no, you have to create in class.
Naga: Which one? Sorry, in class, I told you, inside the notebooks folder, create a .env file.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Naga: Okay, I'll move that to VMV file, EMV file here.
Krish NAik: you need to enter the OpenAI API key and the DB URL, the database URL.
Krish NAik: So… Check that the connection is working.
Naga: Yeah, I have the END Sabha.
Naga: I'll cut on this one.
Naga: I don't think I might need to restart the kernel, I think that…
Krish NAik: Yes, you have to restart the kernel. Once you have that, then only it will detect.
Krish NAik: And you have to actually do the test of that. First of all, it's working or not, the database connection. That's why I provide you that particular script.
Naga: The… okay, that.
Krish NAik: the contest key.
Naga: The contest.
Krish NAik: At the end, it will be… there will be a script at the end.
Krish NAik: Supervisors contest.
Naga: Contest, okay, on this one, okay, let me.
Krish NAik: If you run this file, because the DB URL will be the same in both the NV files, it will be picking up from the root directory of the project, and then it will try to execute.
Naga: We'll do CTRL-C here, -Oh.
Naga: PR, SuperVoice context, okay? Python… quantum.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can say connected, it means that it's fine. Now, restart the notebook and start your execution, I think it should work fine.
Naga: Welcome.
Naga: Cardinal again.
Naga: So it's final starter, Rano.
Naga: It's now trying this.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, hi, Paul. I have modified the project folder, but still I'm seeing the same issue.
Naga: Yeah, same thing, it's a different error coming. It's saying connection to the server, boot failed, connection to the service failed, shuttle password.
Naga: notification fielded with a postcards.
Krish NAik: Because if here the connection is taking place, just check both the DB URLs are exactly the same.
Naga: There is a DB URL in where? Like, this one EMRL?
Krish NAik: In the other ENV file, show me that ENV file, what do you have in that ENV file?
Naga: This is one year in the file, which is how.
Krish NAik: That is the root folder, that is for your FastAPI application. I'm talking with respect to the notebook, as you were showing me the.
Naga: Notebook one. Okay, this is a notebook full. This is notebook only, I think.
Krish NAik: This is within the notebook, then again, you have the same database URL here also, no? If it is a different, then it will simply throw you the error.
Naga: It is the… this is the database URL.
Naga: Oh, okay.
Krish NAik: In both the places, it's same, please have a check on that.
Naga: And that's another problem.
Krish NAik: Because in one place, if it is getting connected, in the other place also, it should be connected as well.
Naga: on rational.
Krish NAik: Here, Sampat, show me your screen.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, yes, I bought this one.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you have done, RAG, inside RAG, you have Multidata RAG project, okay, you have manually created the folder, that's why the name is coming different, fine. Alright, now, rest of the things you have updated.
Krish NAik: Alright, now go back.
Krish NAik: Show me, show me, make the terminal bigger.
Krish NAik: when you are showing with argument logs, make it always big, yes. So it's saying that, okay, start process, and starting only it failed.
Krish NAik: mean… Back project involved data, import, scroll down.
Krish NAik: Down, down, down, down, down, no. No module found, app.
Krish NAik: Because… okay, do a Ctrl-C right now in front of me.
Krish NAik: Ctrl-C.
Krish NAik: Again, why you are inside the app folder?
Krish NAik: Why you are inside the app folder? Yes, from here, execute.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Okay, that's my mistake, yeah.
samapth reddy vummanthala: That's why it is not able to fetch the app folder.
Krish NAik: You have to execute it from the project directory. Probably we have kept a print statement because of that, it's showing, I think.
Krish NAik: Wait, wait, wait, right now.
Krish NAik: Wait, wait. First of all, wait, the app has not started yet.
Krish NAik: Wait. Go back to the terminal, check the logs. Okay, now the application has started.
Krish NAik: You will see Application Startup Complete Info, then only go back. Okay, now you can open the docs.
Krish NAik: Go back to the browser.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, not running.
samapth reddy vummanthala: If there's any… There's no error logs.
samapth reddy vummanthala: I'll go back to the.
Krish NAik: the browser, go back to the browser. These are logs, later on, you can check. Right now, test. Yes. Now, Naga, you tell me.
Naga: Yeah, yeah, the result is coming now.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Naga: No, the thing is somewhere it got down, it stuck.
Naga: And, so, so for testing, right, I need to…
Naga: test with, like, I think from the app, how do I need to… in this.
Krish NAik: You have to go inside the routes, no, and you have to check the routes. That's the thing I've discussed in the class also.
Naga: Oh.
Naga: It's… oh, app I have to start, okay. So, routes is, where is the route, I assume? Sorry.
Krish NAik: Routes are fast API routes. Once you start your Fast API API application, then you will get the routes.
Naga: Okay, okay, application account.
samapth reddy vummanthala: Yeah, voila. It's coming. Whole checkup is coming. Thank you.
Krish NAik: Alright, Samput.
Naga: They started the week one,
Naga: Doctors are related to organize families.
Krish NAik: Wait for the application to start.
Naga: Perfect.
Krish NAik: you check the logs, wait for the logs, it will say the application has started in the info. That's why I've kept the info label logs.
Krish NAik: So that everybody can understand what is going on.
Naga: Yes. Here, your OPIC monitoring will fail, because you have not passed the OPI key, that is fine, OPIC.
Krish NAik: Okay, connected to Pinecone, alright. Now the initialization is done, now you can open.
Naga: Slash dogs.
Naga: Celestial.
Naga: Okay, now…
Krish NAik: Now, these are routes. Now, these routes you have to test.
Naga: So, for example, go below, yes, this is the health route, you can try it out.
Naga: the route.
Naga: Okay. Educated.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Naga: Some help is come, right? Islam. Yes, help is true.
Naga: Embedding service and this one, okay. Then next is, okay, yeah, so, why the successful response, or whatever it's saying? Then documents, shall I upload some document here, or…
Krish NAik: Yes, upload.
Naga: Okay.
Naga: You can upload some try it out, okay?
Naga: Choose file,
Naga: That is incorrect.
Naga: direction.
Naga: So, parameters… Yeah, here I chose it, okay, so execute, sorry.
Naga: And I will ask the question down, right?
Naga: It's executing something.
Naga: So, will it produce any log?
Naga: Any clients or the one.
Krish NAik: Based on the document size, it takes time, you have to wait.
Naga: Hmm. It's just a one-pager document only?
Krish NAik: One page of document, it should be faster.
Naga: Or maybe it's not a good document, not a good quality document, I think, yeah, sorry, I think that's a problem.
Naga: But still, it should do not. Like, it's a kind of image. Will it take it, an image? Like, photos?
Naga: Maybe I'll take a different one, I'm sorry, it's not a good…
Krish NAik: look into the terminal logs. Whenever you are uploading, it will show you how many chunks you are creating. Look into terminal.
Naga: Looking to, which terminal, like…
Krish NAik: Which terminal, from where you have started the app in that terminal only will look, no?
Naga: Yeah, this one, hold on.
Naga: So it's doing something, multi-cache…
Naga: Is it, extra… is enabled for this report? But it's not giving nothing.
Krish NAik: It's telling a lot of user warnings are coming in your system.
Naga: My pleasure.
Krish NAik: You can see, to support symbols, symbolic links, you either need to activate the weather mode. Okay, so this is… it's still now in wait phase. Wait.
Krish NAik: Your system will take time.
Naga: Yeah, that PDF is kind of a very bad PDF, either.
Krish NAik: And it doesn't matter right now, just check any PDF we should be uploading, and the chunks should be created, that is the priority.
Naga: That's just human.
Naga: I'm gonna go back to this, and then, we're still doing something.
Naga: What about the base.
Naga: Yeah, it's so much…
Naga: multi-round, user volume…
Naga: He's not installed.
Naga: No detail are the…
Krish NAik: Because you have so many warnings, HFXCT packages not installed, falling back to regular, I don't know, like, generally this doesn't come. If it is suggesting you, now you can see, generating 15 chunks, okay, now, yes, this is done.
Naga: Yeah, can I ask some questions to that now?
Krish NAik: Yes, ask some question.
Naga: So, this is, click on… this one, yeah. Now it's done something, it's done something. No.
Naga: Where can I ask the question here? Query? Is it query?
Krish NAik: Got it.
Naga: Post, post the doc. Okay, post… Okay, question, okay.
Naga: That's not enabled, I don't know why.
Krish NAik: You have to click on try it out.
Naga: Both sides of them.
Naga: Question? Okay.
Naga: Who is Kamala? I don't have anyone. Yeah, okay, yeah, it's giving out information after something.
Naga: What is this plan?
Naga: Yeah, I think it is working.
Naga: Wow.
Krish NAik: This will work.
Krish NAik: If one is working, I know the other will also work.
Naga: So, basically, it is building a SQL query, and then getting the detail of the… Oh, okay.
Naga: Yeah, yeah. It is good.
Naga: Don't expecting.
Krish NAik: redundant.
Naga: What is the bill? What is the rate?
Naga: Oh.
Naga: Oh, that was a…
Krish NAik: now you can do those testing yourself. Alright, so majorly, I think for everybody, majorly the issues got solved. Okay, so in the next class, then, we will start with the scratch implementation.
Krish NAik: Directly from, our mail source.
Krish NAik: I think that will be the main agenda. So, next two classes, it will be complete, the Project 2 implementation from scratch that we'll be doing, and even the AWS setup on Saturday. So, just be sure you have your AWS accounts with you guys.
Krish NAik: Beh.
Krish NAik: So, let's conclude the session for today. Okay, so today's session was pretty much a small one, but I hope, for everybody, the app is up and working. If there is any issue, please post it in the community group. Okay, from there, I will be picking up.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so bye-bye, everyone. Thanks a lot, okay? So this project will be a little bit complex, but…
Krish NAik: You're learning, for sure, as compared to the first project, it will be much higher.
Krish NAik: Thank you, everyone.
Krish NAik: Okay, so bye-bye, see you guys next week.